<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[jr0cket]]></title>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[community developer]]></subtitle>
  <link href="categories/events/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jr0cket.co.uk/"/>
  <updated>2022-01-02T20:20:15.310Z</updated>
  <id>http://jr0cket.co.uk/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[John Stevenson]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[john@jr0cket.co.uk]]></email>
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Why Go to a Conference]]></title>
    <link href="http://jr0cket.co.uk/2014/03/why-go-to-a-conference.html"/>
    <id>http://jr0cket.co.uk/2014/03/why-go-to-a-conference.html</id>
    <published>2014-03-08T16:07:47.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-02T20:20:15.310Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There are a great many developer and tech conferences to got to and the numbers are increasing.  Some of these conferences are free or free if you speak or volunteer, some are relativley cheap and some you may be able to persuade your company to pay for.  But why should you even consider going to a conference in the first place?</p>
<a id="more"></a>
<h1 id="As-a-speaker"><a href="#As-a-speaker" class="headerlink" title="As a speaker"></a>As a speaker</h1><p>So why go to a conference as a speaker?</p>
<p>Well the most obvious benefit is that you will probably get into the whole conferences for free.  If you are speaking about something relevant to the company you work for, they may also pay for your travel &amp; hotel expenses (if required).</p>
<p>Speakers can sometimes invite a friend along to the conference too.</p>
<p>Being a speaker at an event is a good way to get to network with the other speakers at the event.  The organisers some times arrange a speakers dinner the evening before, so as well as getting wined and dined by the organisers you get more of a chance to talk with the other speakers and build good relationships.</p>
<h2 id="Explaining-something-verifies-your-understanding"><a href="#Explaining-something-verifies-your-understanding" class="headerlink" title="Explaining something verifies your understanding"></a>Explaining something verifies your understanding</h2><p>In fact, presenters are usually the ones that get the most from a conference, they present there ideas and then have some one in the crowd as for “a real world example”.  Putting yourself on the spot like that and learning how to deal with it puts you in a good place when you go back to work and have to deal with all sorts of other less than plesant situations.</p>
<p>Its fun being a speaker, you get respect for just standing up in front of a crowd and speaking.</p>
<p>Its a great way to develop your career.  Are you tired of boring interview questions or dumb tests that only test your memory rather than your understanding?  A reputation of speaking at conferences goes a long way to cut through the crap that you often get at interview time.</p>
<p>Working a crowd at a presetation helps inmprove you team skills and helps you understand how you can inspire and influence people.  It is good training for real leadership.</p>
<p>I dont know of any speakers who ended up on the IT scrap-heap…</p>
<h1 id="As-an-attendee"><a href="#As-an-attendee" class="headerlink" title="As an attendee"></a>As an attendee</h1><p>Attending a conference is a chance to get away from work for a few days and actually step back and think about things.  It can be hard to see the big picture in terms of what you are trying to achieve at work when you are head down getting things done (or fire fighting).</p>
<p>Its good to find out what is happening in technology and see how others are applying the same tools and languages you use to great value.  Even some small change in approach can make you more effective.</p>
<p>There is an opportunity to meet a lot of new people and discuss conserns and ideas with each other.  Its a great chance to meet people in your situation and do some venting, talk about how you face your challenges, swap ideas and </p>
<p>Find out what people are doing and what they are excited about, why they get out of bed in the morning</p>
<p>Its good to put conferences on your CV - shows initiative, shows you are interested in learing and developing yourself</p>
<p>Its a great way to learn new things, or at least learn what things you should be looking at for the next 6 months - unless you like turning up to work and doing the same old crap week in week out !!!</p>
<p>It gives you something to talk about with your team when you get back to work, something other than what was on TV last night.</p>
<p>How boring is it to just work with someone who just turns up 9-5 and does nothing else.  I want to work with people who are inspired, passionate and enthusiastic about what they do.  As an employer, why would you ever hire someone who wasnt like this ??  Oh yes, because that employer has either no respect for thier staff or just wants them to do some grunt work - the IT factory in its worse sense.</p>
<p>Most employeers have no idea about IT and many do not need to know that much, except that they should respect the knowledge workers they hire and empower them to deliver the best possible service they can.  Unfortunately managment has been trained to measure and manage people like a time and cost study, rather than considering the value that their staff can bring them.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Blinkered Manager: “What happens if I train my staff and they all leave”<br>Enlightened developer: “What happens if you dont train your staff and they all stay”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>If you want a successful business then you need successful people, people who will help you drive the business forward and not be a blocker to the delivery of your ideas. </p>
<p>There have been quite a few organisations that are now able to deliver at the speed of thought, deploying hundereds of ideas a day and getting the best feedback you can in the world - the customers recieving your service.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>There are a great many developer and tech conferences to got to and the numbers are increasing.  Some of these conferences are free or free if you speak or volunteer, some are relativley cheap and some you may be able to persuade your company to pay for.  But why should you even consider going to a conference in the first place?</p>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="presenting" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/tags/presenting/"/>
    
      <category term="events" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/categories/events/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Hackference Aftermath - Hacking the Weekend for Fun & Prizes]]></title>
    <link href="http://jr0cket.co.uk/2013/09/hackference-aftermath-hacking-weekend.html.html"/>
    <id>http://jr0cket.co.uk/2013/09/hackference-aftermath-hacking-weekend.html.html</id>
    <published>2013-09-25T01:03:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-02T20:20:15.302Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://2013.hackference.co.uk/img/hackference_logo.png" class="img-thumbnail">
<p>I’ve added a new work to my vocabulary: <strong>Hacklag</strong>.  Hackference Birmingham left me totally exhausted and yet once I had recovered I was highly motivated to try the things I had experienced there.  So I am sharing my experiences from the weekend hackathon of fun, discovery and glorious food.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Previously I <a href="http://jr0cket.co.uk/2013/09/hackference-aftermath-amazing-polyglot.html">shared my experiences of the Hackference polyglot conference</a>, detailing what I learnt from the great talks there.</p>
</blockquote>
<a id="more"></a>
<h1 id="The-Hackathon-weekend"><a href="#The-Hackathon-weekend" class="headerlink" title="The Hackathon weekend"></a>The Hackathon weekend</h1><img src="http://bean2bed.com/skin/frontend/default/bean/images/slide/4.jpg" class="img-thumbnail">
<p>The venue at Boxxed had a great open space that encouraged people to collaborate and provide an open and friendly workspace.  There was plenty of table space, huge bean bags that turned into beds and sofas to lounge in, not that many of us took the time to lounge until the early hours of Sunday morning!</p>
<p>We started Saturday with some overviews of API’s and developer tools from the sponsors of the Hackathon, including <a href="http://pusher.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pusher</a>, <a href="http://www.heroku.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Heroku</a>, <a href="https://www.twilio.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Twillio</a>, PayPal, Paymill, CloudFoundry and a few others.  Each sponsor also described what prizes they had on offer.  With a trip to their offices in Berlin, <a href="https://soundcloud.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SoundCloud</a> had arguably the best prize on offer.</p>
<h1 id="Food-glorious-food"><a href="#Food-glorious-food" class="headerlink" title="Food glorious food"></a>Food glorious food</h1><img src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ph9Hh_m30S0/UkIcY1ioJWI/AAAAAAAALo4/0OGMV8JqrM8/s1600/20130901_122932.jpg" class="img-topic"> 
<p>During the day there was delicious food on offer and plenty for everyone.  A good job as I didn’t get round to eating anything on conference day, unless you count a pint of Guinness as food :)  I really enjoyed the curry of the Saturday evening and I also had a few cups of curry to keep me going through the night as there was a bit left over. </p>
<h1 id="Friendly-collaborative-developer-crowd"><a href="#Friendly-collaborative-developer-crowd" class="headerlink" title="Friendly, collaborative developer crowd"></a>Friendly, collaborative developer crowd</h1><p>I met lots of great people at the event and I think I spoke to everyone there, it was a very friendly event.  Some of the developers were quite experienced and some were relatively new and some were quite young and will become the future of our developer communities.  Everyone got involved and seemed to have learnt a lot over the weekend.</p>
<h1 id="My-favourite-hacks-from-the-event"><a href="#My-favourite-hacks-from-the-event" class="headerlink" title="My favourite hacks from the event"></a>My favourite hacks from the event</h1><img src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-D5BN3ESCXNA/UkIf2EzBQ1I/AAAAAAAALq8/HwZZJdXtU0I/s1600/20130831_164207.jpg" class="img-code"> 
<p>There were some great ideas on the go during the hackathon, some that were perhaps a little too ambitious but great to see anyway.  There were over 20 hacks on show at the end and as Mike asked me to be one of the judges, it was a challenge to choose the most deserving hacks after everyone had put so much effort into them.</p>
<p>This is a top 5 of my own favourites from the hack, not the actual winners (although there is some crossover).</p>
<h2 id="5-HackSocNotts"><a href="#5-HackSocNotts" class="headerlink" title="5 - HackSocNotts"></a>5 - HackSocNotts</h2><p>I’ve met the team from HackSocNotts at a few hackathons now and they are a really enthusiastic and creative bunch.  This time they were building a visual hack that would be a light-show at this years freshers fair, demonstrating how much fun you can have if you join in.</p>
<p>The team assembled a strip of 32 LEDs all wired up to an <a href="http://www.arduino.cc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Arduino</a> board and controlled by a Raspberry Pi.  The aim was to allow anyone to set up a pattern with the lights via a simple website, making it very interactive.  The hack consisted of two node programs communicating over web-sockets, firing codes into the register of the strip.  The website was a simple Twitter bootstrap affair.  The biggest technical challenge was working with node and the LED hardware, but eventually they got it working some time in the middle of the night.</p>
<h2 id="4-Uber-hack"><a href="#4-Uber-hack" class="headerlink" title="4 - Uber hack"></a>4 - Uber hack</h2><img src="http://blog.uber.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/New-Logo-Vertical-Dark.jpg" class="img-topic">
<p>Uber is a taxi ordering service which you can use from your mobile phone.  You can see where the available cars are in your area.  What the Uber team managed to do is reverse engineer the Uber API so they could track their fleet of cars from anywhere in the world.  By entering a location in their web app, the Uber cars were shown on a Google map.  It was a great app and a very slick presentation, very surprising since the team consisted of a 19 year old and a 16 year old.</p>
<h2 id="3-Code-Tennis"><a href="#3-Code-Tennis" class="headerlink" title="3 - Code Tennis"></a>3 - Code Tennis</h2><p>Created by <a href="https://twitter.com/teabass" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Andrew Nesbitt</a>, <a href="http://code-tennis.herokuapp.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Code tennis</a> is a fun way to improve your skills with Git, especially when it comes to working with Git as a team.  In the game you can be as Machiavellian as you like, thinking of commits that will actively cause your opponent more of a challenge when merging your commits to their local repository and pushing those commits to the shared Github repository.</p>
<img src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-dM2mTiykXzA/UkIWKc_eVyI/AAAAAAAALks/vZBSA1YB-jY/s1600/code-tennis.png" class="img-code">
<p>The game involves each developer taking it in turns to push code to a shared repository on Github.  A <code>git push</code> flips the access to the Github repository to the other player, so you have to take it in turns.</p>
<p>However, whist waiting for your turn to push you can make local commits.  Deciding on what to commit and how much of a challenge you can make for your opponent will help you understand how much you really know about the power of Git.</p>
<p>All changes pushed to the shared Github repository get automatically published onto Github pages.</p>
<p>The name “Code Tennis” comes from the gamification of image creation by graphic designers.  They play Layer Tennis where each graphic designer takes it in turn to create a graphic on one layer of an image.  Each turn adds another layer to the image by those playing the game to get an interesting mix of styles and very different end results.</p>
<p>As with graphic designers, playing code tennis get helps you discover different ways of using Git repositories in a fun way.  Hopefully you will use these new skills for the benefit of your team :)</p>
<h1 id="2-Distributed-speakers"><a href="#2-Distributed-speakers" class="headerlink" title="2 - Distributed speakers"></a>2 - Distributed speakers</h1><img src="http://www.iainclaridge.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/munny_speakers.jpg" class="img-thumbnail"> 
<p>Using Twillio, <a href="http://sydlawrence.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Syd Lawrence</a> set up a simple website that that streamed sound to any mobile that called a particular telephone number.  Syd got a whole bunch of use to call the number and within a few seconds we had all become a distributed speaker system, blasting out Rick Askley!</p>
<p>It was a simple idea that made good use of an API to get the hack done.  It also reminded me of fun things done by seb.ly with graphics and audience interaction.</p>
<p>As Syd was also judging then we couldn’t give him a prize (he wouldn’t accept one anyway).  I hope that if he takes it forward then it is used for other songs that Rick Askley</p>
<h1 id="1-Super-pirate-battleships"><a href="#1-Super-pirate-battleships" class="headerlink" title="1 - Super pirate battleships"></a>1 - Super pirate battleships</h1><p>This was an amazing hack.  The team built a fully working game that looked really good and worked very well, they also made the game environment dynamic.  Their game pulled a music track from SoundCloud and as it played the track was analysed and the pattern of the soundwave was used to determine where obstacles and power-ups should be placed during game-play.</p>
<div class="video-container"><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/6rJqpdJffac" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>
<p>Top prize winner: Super Pirate Battleships video cortesy of <a href="https://twitter.com/J0lley" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mark Jolley</a>)</p>
<h1 id="In-Summary"><a href="#In-Summary" class="headerlink" title="In Summary"></a>In Summary</h1><p>There were lots of really great hacks I havent mentioned and so would just like to thank everyone for there hacks and making it a really entertaining and enlightening weekend.</p>
<p>You can see more of the hacks by looking at some of the <a href="http://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLsTreukqJm95hm0VQD4QWITpFKISaX_l_" target="_blank" rel="noopener">videos from Mark Jolley</a> of the hack showcase, or visiting the <a href="https://www.hackerleague.org/hackathons/hackference/hacks" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hackference page on Hacker league</a>.  If you are not at work and feeling brave you can even check out <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/obbsb367qorijw0/syd-twerkin.mov" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Syd Lawrences’ twerking Video</a> or the great photos from <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/andypiper/with/9628126743/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Andy Piper</a> and <a href="https://plus.google.com/u/0/photos/117080433375668558463/albums/5927331270432594721" target="_blank" rel="noopener">myself</a>.</p>
<p>I really hope Mike runs Hackference Birmingham again as I had such a great time.  Hopefully he will get more volunteers to help him next time as he did a huge amount of work to make this all happen.  Thanks Mike, you did a fantastic job.</p>
<p>Thank you.<br><a href="https://twitter.com/jr0cket" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@jr0cket</a></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<img src="http://2013.hackference.co.uk/img/hackference_logo.png" class="img-thumbnail">
<p>I’ve added a new work to my vocabulary: <strong>Hacklag</strong>.  Hackference Birmingham left me totally exhausted and yet once I had recovered I was highly motivated to try the things I had experienced there.  So I am sharing my experiences from the weekend hackathon of fun, discovery and glorious food.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Previously I <a href="http://jr0cket.co.uk/2013/09/hackference-aftermath-amazing-polyglot.html">shared my experiences of the Hackference polyglot conference</a>, detailing what I learnt from the great talks there.</p>
</blockquote>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="events" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/categories/events/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Hackference Aftermath - Amazing Polyglot Conference]]></title>
    <link href="http://jr0cket.co.uk/2013/09/hackference-aftermath-amazing-polyglot.html.html"/>
    <id>http://jr0cket.co.uk/2013/09/hackference-aftermath-amazing-polyglot.html.html</id>
    <published>2013-09-17T09:36:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-02T20:20:15.302Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://2013.hackference.co.uk/img/hackference_logo.png" class="img-thumbnail">
<p><a href="http://hackference.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hackference</a> Birmingham was the first event I had been to that was both a conference and a hackathon.  Both parts excelled my expectations.  Its also the first big event I’ve been to in Birmingham outside the national exhibition centre (NEC) and the developers in Birmingham made me feel very welcome. </p>
<p>This is a reflection of what happened at the conference part of <a href="http://hackference.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hackference Birmingham</a>.</p>
<a id="more"></a>
<h1 id="The-Speaker-line-up"><a href="#The-Speaker-line-up" class="headerlink" title="The Speaker line up"></a>The Speaker line up</h1><p>I described this as a polyglot developer conference as there were great talks from developers with backgrounds in PHP, Clojure, Javascript, Node, Java and Ruby.  There are many things that are common between languages, like good design, so its great to see ideas from such a broad spectrum.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I may have taken some poetic license with my description of these talks.  This represents my interpretation of those talks and not necessarily what the speakers were actually saying!  Hopefully its close enough…</p>
</blockquote>
<h1 id="Why-don’t-you-go-out-and-do-something-less-boring-instead"><a href="#Why-don’t-you-go-out-and-do-something-less-boring-instead" class="headerlink" title="Why don’t you go out and do something less boring instead?"></a>Why don’t you go out and do something less boring instead?</h1><p>The opening talk by <a href="http://sydlawrence.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Syd Lawrence</a> was very inspiring and a great way to wake up sleepy developers.  Syd encouraged us to <em>stop watching Coronation Street and try tech stuff out instead</em>.  Its easier than you think and there are lots of API’s, tools and frameworks that make it even easier.  (the amount of hardware hacking in hackthons demonstrates how easy it is to get something working).</p>
<p>Its easy to make excuses not to try something new but every day it is getting easier and easier to try things out.  Over the last decade software development has truly become soft and malleable, so code is easy to change and using tools like Git its easy to change that code without hanging yourself.</p>
<p>In the last few years the same level of tinkering and malleability also applies to hardware.  With arduino &amp; raspberry pi kits along with tonnes of components its easy to build something with hardware and then pull it apart and build something else.  Electronics is after all a lego box of components for you to experiment with.</p>
<p>This encouragement from Syd reminded me of the BBC children’s TV show from the past, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Why_Don" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Why dont you?</a> which inspired me to go out and do fun stuff when I was so much younger.  Now I am older, why shouldnt I have just as much fun :)</p>
<h1 id="API-Design-Give-developers-some-love"><a href="#API-Design-Give-developers-some-love" class="headerlink" title="API Design - Give developers some love!"></a>API Design - Give developers some love!</h1><p><a href="http://www.lornajane.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lorna Jane Mitchell</a> gave a run down of the do’s and don’t of API design. Having developed a number of API’s herself you could hear the experience dripping from her words.</p>
<p>I cant do justice to her talk so I suggest you take a look at some of the quotes I pulled from her talk and if you like what you read then go and <a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920028291.do?cmp=af-code-book-product_cj_9781449365080_7049572" target="_blank" rel="noopener">buy her book</a>… you wont regret it.</p>
<ul>
<li>HTTP has status codes, so use them to understand what is going on</li>
<li>Content should be determined by header content type rather than URLs</li>
<li>SOAP is great for Java/C# devs as they have a button that generates a SOAP service, hainving to  type a lot of XML is not nice</li>
<li>REST is great but has “enthusiasts” that tell you your REST is wrong.  Taking a pragmatic approach to REST is better rather than trying to reach for perfection</li>
<li>Build a heartbeat into your API, this provides a simple self help mechanism to check API is being used correctly by developers</li>
<li>Consistence in experience will make a big difference when devs are choosing to use your API.  If your API is too erratic or unstable then you will loose your community. </li>
<li>Cache GET requests to help scale when you become popular.  Your API can use same principles as when caching static assets</li>
<li>Handling errors is a measure of how good your API is perceived developers</li>
<li>Tokens are so much nicer to use than a username/password combo for access control. OAuth2 is really nice to use now.</li>
</ul>
<p>To me, the main point that Lonra Jane was getting across is that API designers need to engage with the community of developers to gain adoption and have a successful API.</p>
<h1 id="Getting-Git-and-Github"><a href="#Getting-Git-and-Github" class="headerlink" title="Getting Git and Github"></a>Getting Git and Github</h1><p>Yours truly gave an impromptu talk about Git and Github, providing the audience a whole heap of tips and tricks to get the most out of these distributed version control tools.  For those just trying out Git for the first time, I created a <a href="http://jr0cket.github.io/developer-guides/git-quickstart-guide.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Git quickstart guide</strong></a>.</p>
<p>I also created a visual guide to Git and Github workflows:</p>
<img src="http://jr0cket.github.io/developer-guides/git-and-github-workflow.png" class="img-code">
<p>The tips I shared included:</p>
<ul>
<li><p>using <code>git add</code> to help you be more selective in what you are committing without having to learn how to cherry pick</p>
</li>
<li><p>using <code>git stash</code> to keep your work when you fall behind a shared remote (which I am sure we never do, right)</p>
</li>
<li><p>configuring <code>git log</code> to be more valuable by showing a graph with repos, branches and tags (see my <a href="https://github.com/jr0cket/dot-files-ubuntu/blob/master/.gitconfig" target="_blank" rel="noopener">.gitconfig file</a> for examples of aliases used for git log and other useful short cuts)</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>I also talked about the workflow around Git and Github and encouraged people to keep it simple.  You can always add more to your workflow when needed, but jumping straight into something as involved as git flow may not give you the best experience.  When you are comfortable with git and are working on team projects, then take a look at Git flow and see if its for you.  There is <a href="http://jeffkreeftmeijer.com/2010/why-arent-you-using-git-flow/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a good overview of Git flow by Jeff Kreeftmeijer</a>.</p>
<h1 id="Boosting-your-JavaScript-projects-with-Yeoman-Bower-and-Grunt"><a href="#Boosting-your-JavaScript-projects-with-Yeoman-Bower-and-Grunt" class="headerlink" title="Boosting your JavaScript projects with Yeoman, Bower and Grunt"></a>Boosting your JavaScript projects with Yeoman, Bower and Grunt</h1><p>The ease in which a decent sized JavaScript project was created as part of the live demo in this talk by <a href="http://hackference.co.uk/speakers#martyn-davies" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Martyn Davies</a> has put this tool combo (<a href="http://yeoman.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Yeoman, Bower and Grunt</a>) high on my list of new shiny things to try.  I had know about Yoman for a while although hadnt found the excuse to use it.  Now seeing all three tools working together (and me being a command line junkie) I will be using it for my <a href="http://www.heroku.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Heroku</a> demos.  These tools give me a great way to go from scratch to continuous deployment of a live on the web app in less than 30 minutes</p>
<p>I can see Yoman, Bower and Grunt driving most if not all of my JavaScript app development, especially for <a href="http://angularjs.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AngularJS</a>.</p>
<h1 id="All-the-other-great-talks"><a href="#All-the-other-great-talks" class="headerlink" title="All the other great talks"></a>All the other great talks</h1><p>I didn’t see everyone’s talk as I got into some great discussions with some of the speakers and developers attending the event.</p>
<p>I did managed to catch the <a href="http://clojure.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Clojure</a> talk given by <a href="http://2013.hackference.co.uk/speakers#joe-littlejohn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Joe Littlejohn</a> and <a href="http://2013.hackference.co.uk/speakers#mark-godfrey" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mark Godfrey</a>, speaking on how beautiful and powerful the <a href="http://clojure.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Clojure language</a> is.  Its hard to sum it up in 30 minutes and even harder to share the experience without getting the audience to try the language out.  The guys did a good job to get the assembled developers interested.  If you want to know if Clojure is for you, then you can check out my eBook <a href="http://developerpress.com/en/clojure-made-simple-introduction-clojure" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Clojure Made Simple</a>.</p>
<p>I talked to several other developers who were looking at Clojure too and I gave them ideas on <a href="http://jr0cket.co.uk/clojure">how to work with Clojure</a>.  I also helped out a few people with Clojure during the hackathon weekend.</p>
<h1 id="In-Summary"><a href="#In-Summary" class="headerlink" title="In Summary"></a>In Summary</h1><p>Overall this was a great event and I came away felling I learnt a lot more from this conference because of the diversity than I did from very focused conferences like jQuery UK.</p>
<p>In my next article about Hackference Birmingham I’ll <a href="http://jr0cket.co.uk/2013/09/25/hackference-aftermath-hacking-weekend.html/">share my experiences of the Hackathon part of Hackference</a> and tell you about a word I have added to my vocabulary: “Hacklag”.</p>
<p>Thank you.<br><a href="https://twitter.com/jr0cket" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@jr0cket</a></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<img src="http://2013.hackference.co.uk/img/hackference_logo.png" class="img-thumbnail">
<p><a href="http://hackference.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hackference</a> Birmingham was the first event I had been to that was both a conference and a hackathon.  Both parts excelled my expectations.  Its also the first big event I’ve been to in Birmingham outside the national exhibition centre (NEC) and the developers in Birmingham made me feel very welcome. </p>
<p>This is a reflection of what happened at the conference part of <a href="http://hackference.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hackference Birmingham</a>.</p>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="events" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/categories/events/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Hack and Learn With Polyglot Developers in Beautiful Birmingham]]></title>
    <link href="http://jr0cket.co.uk/2013/08/hack-and-learn-with-polyglot-developers.html.html"/>
    <id>http://jr0cket.co.uk/2013/08/hack-and-learn-with-polyglot-developers.html.html</id>
    <published>2013-08-08T14:36:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-02T20:20:15.302Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-LBA04JPAvuM/UgOqJL9PEoI/AAAAAAAAKys/Kv2DM3kmyWg/s1600/hackference_logo.png" class="img-thumbnail"> 
<p><a href="http://hackference.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hackference Birmingham</a> at the end of August is a great opportunity to discover new ideas from polyglot developers at a one day conference, then try those ideas out over a weekend hackathon. </p>
<a id="more"></a>
<p>I’d also forgotten that Birmingham is also a great city to explore, with lots of history and modern design to take in (including the <a href="http://www.fazeleystudios.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fazeley Studios</a> venue).  So I’m going to spend a little extra time discovering all it has to offer.  All of this is within a few minutes walk of Birmingham New Street station.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><a href="http://hackference.co.uk/buy" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sign up by 9th August for the early bird discount </a></p>
</blockquote>
<h1 id="Hackference-The-Conference"><a href="#Hackference-The-Conference" class="headerlink" title="Hackference: The Conference"></a>Hackference: The Conference</h1><img src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-yK4Trdo9HA0/UgOig4F70HI/AAAAAAAAKyM/sVUEtN_FXDU/s1600/Hackference-Fazeley-Studios.png" class="img-topic"> 
<p>The beautiful <a href="http://www.fazeleystudios.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fazeley Studios</a> </p>
<p>The one day conference on Friday offers a diverse set of topics, covering everything from API design, MongoDB, NodeJS, Clojure and even Go.</p>
<p>There is a great line up of experienced speakers, although not the ones you see very often so its a chance to hear some different viewpoints.  I am especially looking forward to hearing from <a href="https://twitter.com/lornajane" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lorna Mitchell</a> about her experiences with API design.</p>
<p>It will also be great to see the guys from Twillio, PayPal and SoundCloud.  All these companies are highly innovative and doing some great things with technology.</p>
<p>As I have been drawn to the <a href="http://clojure.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Clojure</a> language for the last few years it will be great to hear from <a href="http://hackference.co.uk/speakers#joe-littlejohn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Joe Littlejohn</a> and <a href="http://hackference.co.uk/speakers#mark-godfrey" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mark Godfrey</a> on why we should be looking at Clojure and what developers we can gain from the language.  I am intrigued as to how they have been using Clojure at Nokia.</p>
<h1 id="Hackference-The-Hackathon"><a href="#Hackference-The-Hackathon" class="headerlink" title="Hackference: The Hackathon"></a>Hackference: The Hackathon</h1><img src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-ih47wFTJQsE/UgOq-7kfD4I/AAAAAAAAKy4/ihETCQQwppY/s1600/Hackference_-_A_developer_s_dream.png" class="img-topic"> 
<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hackathon" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hackathons</a> are a great chance to focus on learning new things and improving your skills.  With a host of companies there to help you try out their API’s and also win prizes for your app then it truly is a weekend for fun and profit.</p>
<p>I’ll also be running workshops on <a href="http://git-scm.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Git</a>, <a href="http://github.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Github</a> and <a href="https://www.heroku.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Heroku</a>, to help you develop and deploy your applications collaboratively.  I’ll be on hand to help out teams throughout the hackathon as well as writing some apps in Clojure and JavaScript.</p>
<p>An of course its just great to have some time to scratch that itch you have with the stuff you wanted to create but never had time.  With a weekend to focus you can really get in the zone and get creative.</p>
<h1 id="Hackference-The-City"><a href="#Hackference-The-City" class="headerlink" title="Hackference: The City"></a>Hackference: The City</h1><img src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-nqSDbM7BxbU/UgOmWTPGl2I/AAAAAAAAKyc/e5eXoqVxLGQ/s1600/hackference-hotel-rotunda.png" class="img-topic"> 
<p>Birmingham is so easy to get to from most cities, that its a shame I havent taken the time to visit more often.  There are some great hotels to stay at, such at the <a href="http://www.stayingcool.com/birmingham.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rotunda</a> with great views of the city.</p>
<p>If you are looking for culture then there are some world class galleries and museums.  I like the sound of the <a href="http://visitbirmingham.com/explore-birmingham/places/thinktank-incorporating-the-giant-screen/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Thinktank Birmingham Science Museu</a>, a ten themed galleries of immense, inspiring, interactive fun with everything from full size locomotives and aircraft to intestines and taste buds.  Another pleasure would be the planetarium which presents breathtaking images on a 360° domed ceiling.</p>
<p>You can see yourself on TV at <a href="http://visitbirmingham.com/explore-birmingham/places/bbc-birmingham-public-space/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BBC Birmingham’s Public Space</a> at The Mailbox or go on a tour of the BBC studios.  For the indulgent there is also the <a href="http://visitbirmingham.com/explore-birmingham/places/cadbury-world/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cadbury World</a>, a bit like Willy Wonka’s chocolate factory in real life :)</p>
<p>So there is a <a href="http://visitbirmingham.com/what-to-do/attractions/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">whole range of things to do</a> for you or if you want to entertain your family whist you hack.</p>
<h1 id="Hackference-Register"><a href="#Hackference-Register" class="headerlink" title="Hackference: Register"></a>Hackference: Register</h1><p>Talk a look at the conference <a href="http://hackference.co.uk/schedule" target="_blank" rel="noopener">schedule</a> and <a href="http://hackference.co.uk/speakers" target="_blank" rel="noopener">speakers list</a>. If you <a href="http://hackference.co.uk/buy" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sign up</a> before the 9th August you can get the <a href="http://hackference.co.uk/buy" target="_blank" rel="noopener">early bird discount</a> too.</p>
<p>Thank you.<br><a href="https://twitter.com/jr0cket" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@jr0cket</a></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<img src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-LBA04JPAvuM/UgOqJL9PEoI/AAAAAAAAKys/Kv2DM3kmyWg/s1600/hackference_logo.png" class="img-thumbnail"> 
<p><a href="http://hackference.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hackference Birmingham</a> at the end of August is a great opportunity to discover new ideas from polyglot developers at a one day conference, then try those ideas out over a weekend hackathon. </p>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="hackference" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/tags/hackference/"/>
    
      <category term="events" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/categories/events/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Hacked - a Judges View of 500 Developers Creativity in London]]></title>
    <link href="http://jr0cket.co.uk/2013/07/hackedio-500-developers-getting.html.html"/>
    <id>http://jr0cket.co.uk/2013/07/hackedio-500-developers-getting.html.html</id>
    <published>2013-07-26T16:40:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-02T20:20:15.302Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As a judge at <a href="http://hacked.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hacked</a> I was amazed by all the developer talent concentrated into one weekend Hackathon.  There were lots of great ideas realised into apps in such a short space of time.  With 500 developer making up <a href="https://www.hackerleague.org/hackathons/hacked/hacks" target="_blank" rel="noopener">74 teams</a>, it was a challenge to pick out winners. </p>
<p>As Heroku were a major sponsor we decided to give out <a href="http://hacked.io/almanac/heroku/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">prizes</a> to 5 teams, even then it was still a challenge to choose only 5.  We also gave out lots of swag and the t-shirts and moleskin notebooks went down a storm.</p>
<p>With so many diverse creations on show Hacked really lived up to its tagline: Learn ,Build, Share.</p>
<h1 id="Hacked-io-Learn"><a href="#Hacked-io-Learn" class="headerlink" title="Hacked.io: Learn"></a>Hacked.io: Learn</h1><p>I ran a workshop introducing <a href="https://go.heroku.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Heroku</a>, a service to allow developers to deploy there apps quickly without worrying about complex scripts or managing servers.  There were lots of questions about Heroku, <a href="https://postgres.heroku.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Postgres</a> database on demand and other <a href="https://addons.heroku.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">addons</a>.  It was great to see enthusiasm from developers wanting to make the most out of the cloud.</p>
<p>I also ran a workshop on Git, so everyone could put their code up on Github or deploy on Heroku.  As Heroku uses Git for code deployments, then once you are comfortable with basics of Git, deploying in this way seems very natural.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/neilmiddleton" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@neilmiddleton</a> also gave a workshop on the new Heroku API, allowing you to create apps, scale them and monitor them from your own applications.</p>
<p>The BBC, Nokia and lots of other sponsors also gave great talks and help with their APIs.  The BBC had a whole bank of TVs available to hack real TV apps on.</p>
<h1 id="Hacked-io-Build"><a href="#Hacked-io-Build" class="headerlink" title="Hacked.io: Build"></a>Hacked.io: Build</h1><p>Everyone pretty quickly got into teams to start hacking.  There were physical hacks, api hacks, music hacks, TV hacks and some really bizzar hacks going on all through the weekend.</p>
<p>When not running workshops, I interrupted teams hacking away to find out what they were up to.</p>
<p>The Heroku team had a few spare minutes free to build an app too.  Using the Heroku API, we built an app that would show a snippet of your logs when ever someone connected to one of your running apps, showing the location of the users IP on a map.</p>
<h1 id="Hacked-io-Share"><a href="#Hacked-io-Share" class="headerlink" title="Hacked.io: Share"></a>Hacked.io: Share</h1><p>It was great to get so many teams sharing their amazing creations.  The diversity of the crowd produced a feast for the eyes and ears.  I’ve only captured a few of my own highlights in this post.</p>
<h1 id="Getting-Organised"><a href="#Getting-Organised" class="headerlink" title="Getting Organised"></a>Getting Organised</h1><p>One of the apps I liked the most was the <strong>Event board for organiser</strong> by <a href="https://twitter.com/EChesters" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@EChesters</a> as running developer events on the scale of Hacked is a big challenge.  The Hacked team did very well, although having a good app to managing all aspects of an event in real time would help any team run a event more smoothly.  I especially liked the real time alerts mobile app.  Lets hope this team takes the app further.</p>
<img src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-SBMbodpj9fE/UfKrfRx_7rI/AAAAAAAAKwA/f4muQ-9xtfw/s1600/hacked-machines-3d-printing.png" class="img-topic">
<h1 id="Rise-of-the-Machines"><a href="#Rise-of-the-Machines" class="headerlink" title="Rise of the Machines"></a>Rise of the Machines</h1><p>There were many hardware hacks at the event, especially with <a href="http://nodecopter.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">node copters</a>, micro node copters, nano node copters and copters controlled by Playstation Move controllers.  My favourite amongst these was Wild thumper, a node copter that could follow a remote controlled car just by attaching a small ring of lights to the car, that was really cool.  <a href="http://www.arduino.cc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Arduino</a> powered controller for remote controlled car, with <a href="http://www.raspberrypi.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Raspberry Pi</a> camera driving the copter.</p>
<h1 id="The-world-needs-more-cuteness"><a href="#The-world-needs-more-cuteness" class="headerlink" title="The world needs more cuteness"></a>The world needs more cuteness</h1><p>There were cute hacks like the <a href="http://tiny.cc/bunzorcam" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bunzor Cam</a> by <a href="http://www.twitter.com/danielknell" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@danielknell</a>, <a href="http://www.twitter.com/mfujica" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@mfujica</a>, <a href="http://www.twitter.com/motoko_k" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@motoko_k</a> and fudge the rabbit, because there are just not enough cute bunnies on the web.</p>
<p>Other cute hack involved a knitted darlek and a chrome extension that changed any pictures on a web page to that of a cat… great fun if you do a Google image search for dogs and watch them all change to different cats!</p>
<img src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-F6AIhd1p1xY/UfKozY_9lKI/AAAAAAAAKvk/WjFnAnVpZ64/s1600/philps-lightbox-wires.png" class="img-topic">
<h1 id="Let-there-be-light"><a href="#Let-there-be-light" class="headerlink" title="Let there be light"></a>Let there be light</h1><p>It seems the Hue Light boxes from Philips caught a fair bit of attention.  These were a 3 bulb array that you could connect to over WiFi or Ethernet and control the colours and sequencing of the lights.  The most useful hack for me was the BusBulb.  This hack tapped into Transport for London open data on transport and gave you a lighting countdown to when you needed to leave for your bus.  This would save me a lot of checking of my phone for the time and save batter.</p>
<h1 id="The-Hacked-io-Hackathon-Winners"><a href="#The-Hacked-io-Hackathon-Winners" class="headerlink" title="The Hacked.io Hackathon Winners"></a>The Hacked.io Hackathon Winners</h1><p>It was tough deciding on winners when there were so many great submissions to choose from.  I spent time finding out what the teams were building as its hard to get a true picture just from the 90 second demo at the end.</p>
<p>There was one app that all the judges quickly agreed was the winner, FlashMed.  This app was quite simple but provided a very important service, managing a medication regime for the elderly.  Most elderly people have to take a range of medicines and these are all colour coded to help them.  However its easy to forget the schedule you need to take.  So the app connects to a Phillips Hue lightbox and displays the colour of the medication at the time you are supposed to take it.  Once you have taken it then the light will switch off.  If you fall asleep then the light shows which medications you need to catch up on.  Simple and effective</p>
<p>The peoples choice went to the crazy kids who won two giant lego Starwars kits, the death star and millenium falcon.  That should keep them busy next weekend.</p>
<h1 id="The-Heroku-Winners"><a href="#The-Heroku-Winners" class="headerlink" title="The Heroku Winners"></a>The Heroku Winners</h1><img src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Aa5-sCTus4w/UfKpnTsSMlI/AAAAAAAAKvw/sIbH0AMTxy4/s1600/hacked-prizes-heroku-excitement.png" class="img-topic"> 
<h1 id="API-Unifier"><a href="#API-Unifier" class="headerlink" title="API Unifier"></a><a href="https://www.hackerleague.org/hackathons/hacked/hacks/heroku-api-using-restapiunifier" target="_blank" rel="noopener">API Unifier</a></h1><p><a href="https://twitter.com/theNeomatrix369" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@theNeomatrix369</a> created a wrapper around the Heroku API to help Java developers create cool applications easily with the Heroku API.</p>
<p>The API Unifier is a lightweight Java library that brings together a collection of RESTful APIs under one roof!  This simplifies the use and maintenance of dependencies on external APIs. This library creates an abstraction layer between your application and APIs from disparate vendors to increase cohesion, reduce coupling.<div></div></p>
<h1 id="MusicMatch-io"><a href="#MusicMatch-io" class="headerlink" title="MusicMatch.io"></a><a href="https://www.hackerleague.org/hackathons/hacked/hacks/musicmatch" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MusicMatch.io</a></h1><p>MusicMatch is a social music competition where you need to guess the correct 10 second clip to build up points to get you up the leader board.  The quicker you answer the more points you get, but get the answer wrong and you and you lose points.</p>
<p>The application was developed with Nodejs and uses Nokia music API to get the music tracks.  Redis (Heroku addon) is used to manage the leader board and the app was deployed on Heroku.</p>
<h1 id="Boomerang"><a href="#Boomerang" class="headerlink" title="Boomerang"></a><a href="https://www.hackerleague.org/hackathons/hacked/hacks/boomerang" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Boomerang</a></h1><p>This app is a really fun idea and adds a different dimension to the experience at an event.  With Boomerang you take a picture and throw it out there and see what picture you get back in return.  You never get your own picture back, so you get to experience a little of what everyone else at an event experiences.</p>
<p>The team built this as a native android application with a back-end service running on Heroku to manage which images you received.  The app could also be passed to your friends or strangers at the event if they have a NFC enabled phone.</p>
<h1 id="99hours"><a href="#99hours" class="headerlink" title="99hours"></a>99hours</h1><p>This app helps people develop their ideas and get thought the barriers to turn those ideas into apps.  99hours connects people with those ideas  to those who can help them out.  The goal is to create a highly collaborative place to nurture ideas into projects.  This collaboration is realised in features such as feedback from the community on ideas by up-voting, or providing a variation on the kick-starter model and allowing direct donations to a project you want to support.</p>
<h1 id="Pigeon"><a href="#Pigeon" class="headerlink" title="Pigeon"></a>Pigeon</h1><p>Tom Morris created an app called pidgeon as a kind of location brokarage service, a personal api for your location.  Deployed on Heroku, this app has a simple API to post location information into forsquare to give real time updates of where you are.  To display map information on the website, the hack was written using Rails and used MapBox, OpenStreetmap and MogoLab Heroku addon.  Sometimes you want to hide your location, so the app also had rules to hide your location when you are at home or other personal locattions.  To test the app, Tom also used Macosx controlPlane to simulate different networks.</p>
<h1 id="The-Next-Hackathon"><a href="#The-Next-Hackathon" class="headerlink" title="The Next Hackathon"></a>The Next Hackathon</h1><p>It does take a few days for the adreneline and lack of sleep to balance themselves out after a Hackathon.  Lucklly then there is a few weeks before Leeds Hack.  Leeds hack is great, especially if you want to get your children involved in coding.</p>
<p>I’ll be at Hackference Birmingham next, the first event of its kind in Birmingham, so it should be a great event.  I’ll be doing workshops around Heroku &amp; Git and it seems there is lots of interest around Clojure, functional programming on the JVM. </p>
<img src="http://si0.twimg.com/profile_images/3687034314/640a734aa1b7d887be40fedac191679f_normal.jpeg" class="img-topic">
<blockquote><p>Mike Elsmore - I cordially invite everyone who went to <a href="https://twitter.com/HACKEDio" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@HACKEDio</a> to come to <a href="https://twitter.com/hackferencebrum" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@hackferencebrum</a> and help me make something awesome <a href="http://t.co/8lvxK8Qa9e" title="http://hackference.co.uk" target="_blank" rel="noopener">http://hackference.co.uk</a></p>
<footer><strong>ukmadlz</strong><cite><a href="https://twitter.com/ukmadlz/status/359011375110045696" target="_blank" rel="noopener">twitter.com/ukmadlz/status/359011375110045696</a></cite></footer></blockquote>
<p>Thank you.<br><a href="https://twitter.com/jr0cket" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@jr0cket</a></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>As a judge at <a href="http://hacked.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hacked</a> I was amazed by all the developer talent concentrated]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="hackathon" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/tags/hackathon/"/>
    
      <category term="events" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/categories/events/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Hacking for Good at the Accessibility Hackathon]]></title>
    <link href="http://jr0cket.co.uk/2013/06/hacking-for-good-at-accessibility.html.html"/>
    <id>http://jr0cket.co.uk/2013/06/hacking-for-good-at-accessibility.html.html</id>
    <published>2013-06-10T15:32:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-02T20:20:15.302Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-wGEV9bfpLx4/UcVjxp_edtI/AAAAAAAAJxc/EmQZVqvM2Eg/s1600/accessibility_collage_2.jpg" class="img-thumbnail"> 
<p>Its not often you get a chance to make a difference the way people live their lives.  As my role of judge at the recent Accessibility hackathon by Barclays I met lots of teams spending their weekend doing just that.</p>
<p>The hackathon started with an amazing set of stories from the charities involved.  These stories gave the teams a great insight into the challenges people in these communities faced.  The presence of the the accessibility community through the hackathon helped teams stay focused and create relevant apps that would make a significant difference.</p>
<h1 id="The-Charities"><a href="#The-Charities" class="headerlink" title="The Charities"></a>The Charities</h1><img src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-N_FfhpLYUOg/UcVpkH-nddI/AAAAAAAAJyA/tDGOs5J3-Vs/s1600/accessibility-hack-charities-banner.png" class="img-code"> 
<h1 id="Judging-the-Hackathon"><a href="#Judging-the-Hackathon" class="headerlink" title="Judging the Hackathon"></a>Judging the Hackathon</h1><img src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-ep3jXQK20sQ/UcVwLHOAwRI/AAAAAAAAJyQ/Gd0WHl0Bseg/s1600/mm-judging.jpg" class="img-topic"> 
<p>With all the great ideas generated by the teams taking part, it made the judging quite tough.  Although not as tough as hacking an app together in less that one weekend :)</p>
<p>At the end of the hackathon, each team had 3 minutes to present there app, which is really no time at all.  However, as a judge I had been going round the teams over the weekend to get to know them and find out what they were doing.  This also gave me insight into how they had progress over the weekend.  One of the things we were looking for was if the team could carry on developing there apps afterwards, so their capability and cohesiveness played a factor in our final decision.</p>
<p>It was vital to have members of the accessibility community on the <a href="http://accessibilityhack.com/#judges" target="_blank" rel="noopener">judging panel</a> to be able to judge the impact of each app presented.  There were several judges who had physical challenges who related closely to the value of each teams app.</p>
<h1 id="Accessibility-Apps-that-made-a-difference"><a href="#Accessibility-Apps-that-made-a-difference" class="headerlink" title="Accessibility Apps that made a difference"></a>Accessibility Apps that made a difference</h1><p>With 19 teams to choose from, the judges had a challenge on their hands to come up with 3 winners.  At one point we asked if there could be a couple more prizes.  The apps that really stood out for me though were:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Soundbyte</strong> - filtering out noise for different types of hearing loss </li>
<li><strong>Visual-eyes</strong> - creating a very detailed and highly accurate description of the scene in a pictue  (fantastic concept)</li>
<li><strong>Gesture Touch</strong> - controlling HTML5 apps and games simply</li>
<li><strong>Elephants, ears for everyone</strong> -  transcripting conversations in real time</li>
<li><strong>Real assistance</strong> - guiding peoples journeys and assisting the last meters</li>
<li><strong>Say what you mean</strong> - navigate the web by voice</li>
<li><strong>MemoryBox</strong> - helping those suffering dementia to recall memories easily</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="Accessibility-Apps-in-detail"><a href="#Accessibility-Apps-in-detail" class="headerlink" title="Accessibility Apps in detail"></a>Accessibility Apps in detail</h1><p>What follows is a summary of what I thought of some of the apps presents.</p>
<h2 id="Soundbyte"><a href="#Soundbyte" class="headerlink" title="Soundbyte"></a>Soundbyte</h2><p>I really liked the concept this team opened wiht “We have all experienced sound loss”, it helped make the project very relevant.  Also the way the team got everyone to stand up and clap to simulate the experience was very striking.</p>
<p>The project itself was great.  Having a smart phone as a hearing aid takes away some of the stigma around the hearing impaired. Although phones can cancel out background noise in phone calls, this Android application can eat the sounds that you don’t need.  As the app cancels out the background noise in near real time, you can then listen to only that which is valuable, based on filters defined for different types of hearing loss.  The team had already created a number of options to help you find out the best sounds based on a persons hearing ability and situation.</p>
<p>This was a very striking project and is high on the list as it also has implications for a wider audience, not just those with hearing loss.  As the app was available on the Android Play store in about an hour after they presented, the project seemed very sustainable.</p>
<h2 id="Visual-eyes"><a href="#Visual-eyes" class="headerlink" title="Visual-eyes"></a>Visual-eyes</h2><p>This team only came together at the hackathon and found a vision inspired from talks given by the charities.  There vision was simple and very relevant to the theme of the hackathon.  Photos are everywhere and people love to share them with family and friends.  However, its not possible to share photos in an easy way with those who are visually impaired  </p>
<p>Their app, Visual Eyes, returns a meningful description of any picture provided.  I liked that the team used random images from Facebook as they are representative of the images people share.  As the images were random, then you saw how credible the software was at describing the images.  I was very struck how detailed the descriptions could be, including if people were wearing sunglasses!</p>
<p>This app was very impressive and therefore high on my list due to the detail of description of each picture.  The team had already integrated it their app with Facebook and there were many other integration possibilities.  I was very confident this team would carry on developing their app.</p>
<p>The team were looking to open source the whole processing so that costs from 3rd party services are taken out of the process.  The team are also considering the use of tags to help make the description even more relevant.</p>
<h2 id="Real-Assistance"><a href="#Real-Assistance" class="headerlink" title="Real Assistance"></a>Real Assistance</h2><p>This app stood out immediately.  The ability to record your favourite journeys and play them back to help you find your way seemed like a real win for those with vision issues. It would give those people a lot more confidence when they are navigate to their favourite places.</p>
<p>This app could also be useful for a wider audience, for example to help navigate to a place in a new location or a foreign country. </p>
<p>This app really stood out when the final part of the app was shown, the assisted guidance for the last few meters. To be able to call someone who can direct you using the camera on your mobile device and be guided in real time was a great idea.  It can be a challenge finding entrances and then navigating steps and doors, so this is a great way to deal with that issue too.</p>
<p>The app uses existing phone technologies and WebRTC so the team seemed to have a fully working app come time for the demo.</p>
<p>The team had an eye on future features, such as pre-program points of interest (Banks, restaurants).  This demonstrated that they are willing to take this app further.</p>
<h2 id="Gesture-Touch"><a href="#Gesture-Touch" class="headerlink" title="Gesture Touch"></a>Gesture Touch</h2><p>The team created a way of helping those with physical challenges to interact with HTML5 based apps, especially games.  The team created different modes and controls to help users find the best way of interacting.</p>
<p>I liked that the team had simulated using their app using a device that restricted movements in the hand and what they produced looked quite effective.</p>
<p>This team also had future plans for their apps, including integrating voice recognition, so it seems that they will carry on with their development efforts.</p>
<h2 id="Elephants-ears-for-everyone"><a href="#Elephants-ears-for-everyone" class="headerlink" title="Elephants - ears for everyone"></a>Elephants - ears for everyone</h2><p>The team develop a real time transcription of conversations taking place, aimed at those with hearing disabilities.  They had tried to get hold of some Google Class equipment so that they could have had real time sub-titles when talking to other people.</p>
<p>The team instead created a simple and clean mobile app, allowing you to open up a “channel” in which two or more people could talk and the text of their conversation would be displayed in a similar form to modern text apps.</p>
<p>The team did a great demo, although there was some doubt about how effective this would be if there was background noise.  The team seemed keen to keep on with the development if they got positive feedback, so if they can also include filtering of the background noise I believe they have a valuable app.</p>
<h2 id="Say-what-you-mean"><a href="#Say-what-you-mean" class="headerlink" title="Say what you mean"></a>Say what you mean</h2><p>I appreciated that the team invested time in the experience of being blind and accessing the web.  That they discussed ideas with the people from RNIB helped them identify a real need, that the key desire people had was to go faster.  Screen readers linearised the experiences when people acutally wanted a content driven experiences</p>
<p>The app had a very simple user interface, press a key and say a word.  You are then sent to a link that matches that word.  This is acceptable for websites your are familiar with.</p>
<p>For other sites you don’t know well, then its used like a search that returns the links at the start of the page so you don’t have to go hunting for them.</p>
<p>As their app works as a browser extension, then it works for all web sites without specific configuration.</p>
<p>It was great that the team have considered future functionality, like related terms and filtering search criteria.  I can see this app being quite useful to many.</p>
<h1 id="Teams-that-had-a-great-idea-but-had-not-gone-far-enough-with-the-development"><a href="#Teams-that-had-a-great-idea-but-had-not-gone-far-enough-with-the-development" class="headerlink" title="Teams that had a great idea but had not gone far enough with the development"></a>Teams that had a great idea but had not gone far enough with the development</h1><h2 id="Food-for-though"><a href="#Food-for-though" class="headerlink" title="Food for though"></a>Food for though</h2><p>The team had a great presentation and I really appreciated the use of using Alice as a persona to help us understand who the audience was the were trying to reach.</p>
<p>The concern they were talking was memmory loss which affects a great number of people.  Without a good memory your experiences from a human perspective is about having your independence.</p>
<p>The team continued to tell the story around the persona.  Alice does not always eat properly, because she forgets if she hasnt eaten.  The app the team developed reminds Alice of key meals, helps her select from different meals and talks her through the making of the meal she has selected.  The meals can be put together by family members, doctors or nutritionist, to give more diversity to Alice’s diet.</p>
<p>Although this was a great concept, I felt that the team had not developed the application far enough in the time they had.  There were unanswered questions and I hope that the team are able to get more of the app developed.</p>
<h2 id="MemoryBox"><a href="#MemoryBox" class="headerlink" title="MemoryBox"></a>MemoryBox</h2><p>The team chose a really powerful sounding topic, remenicance therapy.  This was a great technique for helping family and friends to engage with those with dementia   By creating a wide range of media to form a collection that would trigger memories about events and people, it would help those with the condition feel more positive and help them relive experiences.</p>
<p>The challenge was to create something that would easily create this experience and be significant improvement on the basic photo collections you can do with many online services.  The app would need to help the supporting family members create these collections easily and relate them to specific memory categories.  An app would also need to help the family members by relating images to each other automatically, I guess in the same way that Amazon relates other products.</p>
<h2 id="Leap-Motion-accessibility-device"><a href="#Leap-Motion-accessibility-device" class="headerlink" title="Leap Motion accessibility device"></a>Leap Motion accessibility device</h2><p>The sole developer on this personally driven project - his grandmother has difficulties with her hands and finds interaction with computing devices almost impossible.  However, she has a very active mind and the developer wanted a way to help her engage with the Internet which most of us take for granted.</p>
<p>The <a href="http://bit.ly/a11yhack" target="_blank" rel="noopener">project</a> was quite simple, more like a proof of concept as no real substantial application was created.  The developer used an open source project and a Chrome extension to support the leap motion device.  Whilst this is a great device, I was looking for something specific to be built from this concept. </p>
<p>Although this was a enthusiastic developer that may create some good ideas, he didnt really create much of an app to realise this concept.</p>
<h2 id="Library-accessibility"><a href="#Library-accessibility" class="headerlink" title="Library accessibility"></a>Library accessibility</h2><p>I liked the idea of improve accessibility of other apps by identifying libraries that apps that are used, then sending in patches to make them have accessibility features.  This was a great effort by one developer, although if its only one developer I was not sure on the impact.  This wasnt an app that made it easier for people to improve libraries or even encourage other developers to get involved.</p>
<p>Its a very worthwhile effort on this sole developers behalf.  I would have like to have seen something that would help lots of other developers do the same thing.</p>
<p>Thank you.<br><a href="https://twitter.com/jr0cket" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@jr0cket</a></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<img src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-wGEV9bfpLx4/UcVjxp_edtI/AAAAAAAAJxc/EmQZVqvM2Eg/s1600/accessibility_collage_2.jpg" class="img-thumbnail"]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="hackathon" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/tags/hackathon/"/>
    
      <category term="events" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/categories/events/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Hack the Tower February 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://jr0cket.co.uk/2013/02/hack-tower-february-2013.html.html"/>
    <id>http://jr0cket.co.uk/2013/02/hack-tower-february-2013.html.html</id>
    <published>2013-02-22T14:08:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-04-30T20:49:23.217Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-6h-4Dv2fnf8/USeAlY8lgwI/AAAAAAAAJFw/OQheQYOK8zs/s1600/tower42-surrounded-by-blue-cranes.jpg" class="img-thumbnail">
<p>When 100 developers and 1 robot signed up for the February edition of Hack the Tower, across many technical communities in London, I could tell it was going to be a big event.</p>
<blockquote><p>Heading out for a full day of coding <a href="https://twitter.com/HackTheTower" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@HackTheTower</a> - excited about what people will create today #LSDC <a href="https://twitter.com/londonscala" target="_blank" rel="noopener">#LondonScala</a> #LJCjug #LdnClj #robots</p>
<footer><strong>@jr0cket</strong><cite><a href="https://twitter.com/jr0cket/status/300151177960628224" target="_blank" rel="noopener">twitter.com/jr0cket/status/300151177960628224</a></cite></footer></blockquote>
<p>Developers arrived from different communities, including</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.meetup.com/london-scala/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">London Scala user group</a></li>
<li><a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/?fromgroups#!forum/london-clojurians" target="_blank" rel="noopener">London Clojure community</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.meetup.com/Londonjavacommunity/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">London Java Community</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.meetup.com/LondonSalesforceDevelopers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">London Salesforce developers</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.meetup.com/london-software-craftsmanship/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">London Software Craftsmanship</a>&gt;</li>
</ul>
<blockquote><p><a href="https://twitter.com/sandromancuso" title="sandromancuso" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@sandromancuso</a> Yeah our little team is awesome, I believe we’re the last ones still coding :) <a href="https://twitter.com/HackTheTower" title="HackTheTower" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@HackTheTower</a> idea is great, I truly enjoy it!</p>
<footer><strong>@balopat</strong></footer></blockquote>
<a id="more"></a>
<h1 id="Starting-the-Hack-day"><a href="#Starting-the-Hack-day" class="headerlink" title="Starting the Hack day"></a>Starting the Hack day</h1><p>Hack the tower is an open space where developers can collaborate on projects.</p>
<p>As the host I encourage people to form groups along share interests or goals, so they can learn things from each other and lean on each others experiences.  To that end, I ask anyone with a project or idea to share it at the start and encourage people to join one of these projets.  Most people had some idea of what they wanted to work on, although quite a few changed their minds when they heard about the robot project.</p>
<p>I spent part of the day working on Clojure projects, including setting up Clojure on Windows 8 (not known as great developer platform).  I also helped people get to grips with git and <a href="http://blog.jr0cket.co.uk/2013/01/git-log-makes-multiple-repos-easier-to.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">managing multiple repositories</a> as well as a guidance on using <a href="http://www.heroku.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Heroku</a> and MongoDB for the London Scala website project.</p>
<h1 id="Cloud-services-powering-Hack-the-Tower"><a href="#Cloud-services-powering-Hack-the-Tower" class="headerlink" title="Cloud services powering Hack the Tower"></a>Cloud services powering Hack the Tower</h1><img src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-qlVcL6zWbjY/TzFMw8PPiGI/AAAAAAAAEbs/-Ozv0X_6mrQ/s1600/github-logo.png" class="img-thumbnail">
<p>Much of what we do at Hack the Tower is powered by cloud services for developers.  Without tools like Github, Heroku and Google search, coding applications would be so much harder.</p>
<p>We got a brief reminder of this when we broke Github :)<br><blockquote><p>…and github is down for maintenance!!! :O <a href="https://twitter.com/HackTheTower" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@HackTheTower</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/londonscala" target="_blank" rel="noopener">#LondonScala</a></p>
<footer><strong>@balopat</strong><cite><a href="http://twitter.com/balopat/status/300232782590914560" target="_blank" rel="noopener">twitter.com/balopat/status/300232782590914560</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>
<p>Luckily Github was not down for long.  As git is distributed, we were able to save our changes locally or topped up on Coffee whist we waited a few minutes for Github to come back.</p>
<h1 id="Dancing-robot-curious-developers"><a href="#Dancing-robot-curious-developers" class="headerlink" title="Dancing robot, curious developers"></a>Dancing robot, curious developers</h1><p>Everyone’s instant favourite project seemed to be the NVO robot.  Its an amazing piece of kit.  Essentially a programmable robot that can by default can play Japanese music and do Tai Chi.</p>
<div class="video-container"><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/rJnjmwtGQuE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>
<p>You can program the robot visually, by dragging and dropping actions and wiring them up together.  You can create a sequence of positions and get the software to work out the moves necessary to go from one position to another.  Just like digital animators use in software like blender.</p>
<p>You can drill down into each of these actions and program the robot in python or several other languages.</p>
<img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/304321293/2442675643_5ffdd15b3b-square_bigger.jpg" class="img-thumbnail">
<blockquote><p>Many thanks to @<a href="https://twitter.com/jr0cket" target="_blank" rel="noopener">jr0cket</a> for organising <a href="https://twitter.com/HackTheTower" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@HackTheTower</a> today! Introduced a bunch of developers to <a href="https://twitter.com/NaoRobot" target="_blank" rel="noopener">#NAORobot</a>, learnt stuff and had fun too</p>
<footer><strong>@davesnowdon</strong></footer></blockquote>
<p>The robot has stereoscopic cameras and can do face recognition, in that it recognises a face when  it is in front of it.  This means the robot will talk to you when you when it looks at you, although it cant tell one face from another by default.  The robot has pressure sensors and fingers so it can interact with its environment.</p>
<blockquote><p><a href="https://twitter.com/HackTheTower" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@HackTheTower</a> <a href="http://t.co/hfUIMWgT" target="_blank" rel="noopener">My view today</a></p>
<footer><strong>@gnorsilva</strong></footer></blockquote>
<h1 id="London-Scala-user-group"><a href="#London-Scala-user-group" class="headerlink" title="London Scala user group"></a>London Scala user group</h1><img src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-kIrzG80xsL4/UMcqsNDxzzI/AAAAAAAAIsU/hKMCeoPdGkk/s1600/lsug-logo.jpeg" class="img-thumbnail">
<p>There were a lot of developers from LSug  group and they ended up split into three smaller groups to focus on different problems.</p>
<p>Some of the team were working with MongoDB, some working on the RSVP via meetup.  All the events displayed on the Lsug website can now be joined directly, without having to visit the meetup site.  Perhaps the total number of Yes RSVP’s can be added to each meetup?</p>
<h1 id="Coding-board"><a href="#Coding-board" class="headerlink" title="Coding board"></a>Coding board</h1><blockquote>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/villademor" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@villademor</a> Experimenting with <a href="http://t.co/ReN3kzR5" target="_blank" rel="noopener">codingboard.org</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/scala&quot;" target="_blank" rel="noopener">#Scala</a> on <a href="https://twitter.com/HackTheTower" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@HackTheTower</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/londonscala" target="_blank" rel="noopener">#LondonScala</a> with <a href="https://twitter.com/balopat" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@balopat</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/gnorsilva" title="gnorsilva" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@gnorsilva</a> among others!</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="http://codingboard.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Coding Board</a> is a small web application allowing developers to share code with each other in a hands-on session.  When we want to talk about the decisions we took as we approached a problem, its  nice to have the code itself shared on the screen in a syntax  highlighted way.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/balopat" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Balint Pato</a> started this project as a <a href="http://blog.balopat.com/2012/12/a-gift-for-christmas-to-the-software-craftsmanship-community.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Christmas gift</a> for the <a href="http://www.meetup.com/london-software-craftsmanship/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">London Software Craftsmanship Community</a> using:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.scala-lang.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Scala</a> and <a href="http://www.scalatra.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Scalatra</a></li>
<li><a href="http://twitter.github.com/bootstrap/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Twitter Bootstrap</a> for the front end framework</li>
<li><a href="http://docs.seleniumhq.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Selenium Webdriver</a> and <a href="http://etorreborre.github.com/specs2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> Specs2</a> for “testing”</li>
<li><a href="http://www.heroku.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Heroku</a> developer cloud service for easy deployment</li>
<li>and no persistence whatsoever..:)</li>
</ul>
<p>The project is under an open source license and the code is <a href="http://github.com/balopat/codingboard" target="_blank" rel="noopener">available on Github</a> for you to clone and fork.</p>
<blockquote><p>we went live: Syntax highlighting on edit, max 24 hours long boards, loads of small fixes, altogether 10 pull requests! <a href="https://twitter.com/HackTheTower" title="HackTheTower" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@HackTheTower</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/londonscala" target="_blank" rel="noopener">#LondonScala</a></p>
<footer><strong>@balopat</strong><cite><a href="https://twitter.com/balopat/status/300286147186282496" target="_blank" rel="noopener">twitter.com/balopat/status/300286147186282496</a></cite></footer></blockquote>
<p>Read <a href="http://blog.balopat.com/2013/02/hack-the-tower-experience.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a blog of the days events</a> for this project from Balint Pato himself.</p>
<blockquote><p><a href="https://twitter.com/balopat" title="balopat" target="_blank" rel="noopener">balopat</a> <a href="http://t.co/FX6Aqc8P" target="_blank" rel="noopener">meetup photos</a> :) <a href="https://twitter.com/HackTheTower" title="HackTheTower" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@HackTheTower</a></p>
<footer><strong>@balopat</strong></footer></blockquote>
<h1 id="London-Clojurians-getting-going-with-Clojure"><a href="#London-Clojurians-getting-going-with-Clojure" class="headerlink" title="London Clojurians - getting going with Clojure"></a>London Clojurians - getting going with Clojure</h1><img src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-te_MuKdFBTQ/TzFLahe2BxI/AAAAAAAAEbY/Bn_JPN_s3qU/s1600/clojure-logo-500x.png" class="img-thumbnail">
<p>Two of us helped out a developer relatively new to Clojure, although they did have some past experience with Lisp.  We helped them get ther environment set up, which was a bit more of a challenge as the were running Windows 8.</p>
<p>Luckily its still fairly easy to set up a working Clojure environment on Windows, although just about every command seemed to ask for the Administrators password!  On the <a href="http://leiningen.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Leiningen website</a>, there is reference to a 3rd party bat file for getting going with windows.  The problem with this bat file is that its dependant on either wget or curl, neither of which were available on this machine.</p>
<p>We got round the problem by manually doing what the leiningen bat file did, downloading the .jar file and putting it in ~/.lein/self-install/…jar</p>
<p>A problem still remand with running lein.  The version in the .bat file was different from the ..jar file, so lein attempted to use and download a different version, which it couldnt find.  As we didnt have curl or wget to download the version in the bat file, we simply changed the bat file manually.</p>
<p>Some other aspects to setting up Clojure on windows 8 included:</p>
<ul>
<li>make sure javac is on the path, we only had java and lighttable failed</li>
<li>install leiningen - there is a bat file or use cygwin</li>
<li>install lighttable</li>
<li>use lein to create a new project and connect to a REPL</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="Salesforce-for-charity"><a href="#Salesforce-for-charity" class="headerlink" title="Salesforce for charity"></a>Salesforce for charity</h1><img src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-TF122Sgsv-4/UPxdX3gUFHI/AAAAAAAAI70/4WG-fXrH-yE/s1600/force_800x800.png" class="img-thumbnail">
<p>Another team formed around the <a href="http://developer.salesforce.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Salesforce platform</a>.  The were developing a tool to extract data from charity sites like Virgin Just Giving, helping fund raising organisations improve their fund-raising capabilities and getting a better view on where funds were coming from.</p>
<p>The data captured is filtered for the valuable data and the tool would allow you to match the incoming data with existing information you have.</p>
<p>The project is open source and <a href="https://github.com/stony-tsit/UK-Fundraising-Salesforce-App" target="_blank" rel="noopener">available on Github</a>.</p>
<h1 id="Java-Java-Java"><a href="#Java-Java-Java" class="headerlink" title="Java, Java, Java"></a>Java, Java, Java</h1><p>A team was also working on Java and some of the technical activity around the  Java Community Process (JCP).  The JCP is a way for others to help shape the future of the Java language and define the specifications for the language.</p>
<h1 id="Coding-through-the-night"><a href="#Coding-through-the-night" class="headerlink" title="Coding through the night?"></a>Coding through the night?</h1><img src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-x6RUGJlfAto/USJUmLxp4BI/AAAAAAAAJEg/KEuS-PZUAZ8/s1600/london-by-night-from-the-tower.png" class="img-thumbnail">
<p>I did wonder at one point if we would still be here coding through Sunday as there were teams coding well into the evening.  By about 6pm everyone had got headed off into the beautiful London night.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/villademor" title="villademor" target="_blank" rel="noopener">villademor</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/sandromancuso" title="sandromancuso" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@sandromancuso</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/HackTheTower" title="HackTheTower" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@HackTheTower</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/balopat" title="balopat" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@balopat</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/gnorsilva" title="gnorsilva" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@gnorsilva</a> we really had a good time Sandro! Shame we couldn’t catch up with you!</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote><p><a href="https://twitter.com/sandromancuso" title="sandromancuso" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sandromancuso</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/villademor" title="villademor" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@villademor</a> Seems you guys are having loads of fun. Shame I could not make it. /cc <a href="https://twitter.com/HackTheTower" title="HackTheTower" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@HackTheTower</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/balopat" title="balopat" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@balopat</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/gnorsilva" title="gnorsilva" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@gnorsilva</a></p>
<footer><strong>@sandromancuso</strong><cite><a href="https://twitter.com/sandromancuso/status/300283052507160576" target="_blank" rel="noopener">twitter.com/sandromancuso/status/300283052507160576</a></cite></footer></blockquote>
<h1 id="Join-us-for-the-next-HackTheTower-event"><a href="#Join-us-for-the-next-HackTheTower-event" class="headerlink" title="Join us for the next HackTheTower event"></a>Join us for the next HackTheTower event</h1><p>Come along and join the fun.  If you are a developer who likes to learn and share experiences with others, then all you need is a laptop and some enthusiasm (laptop optional).</p>
<p>Sign up at either:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.meetup.com/LondonSalesforceDevelopers/events/98334042/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">London Salesforce Developer community</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.meetup.com/london-scala/events/105841122/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">London Scala user group</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.meetup.com/Londonjavacommunity/events/100797272/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">London Java Community</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Thank you.<br><a href="https://twitter.com/jr0cket" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@jr0cket</a></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<img src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-6h-4Dv2fnf8/USeAlY8lgwI/AAAAAAAAJFw/OQheQYOK8zs/s1600/tower42-surrounded-by-blue-cranes.jpg" class="img-thumbnail">
<p>When 100 developers and 1 robot signed up for the February edition of Hack the Tower, across many technical communities in London, I could tell it was going to be a big event.</p>
<blockquote><p>Heading out for a full day of coding <a href="https://twitter.com/HackTheTower" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@HackTheTower</a> - excited about what people will create today #LSDC <a href="https://twitter.com/londonscala" target="_blank" rel="noopener">#LondonScala</a> #LJCjug #LdnClj #robots</p>
<footer><strong>@jr0cket</strong><cite><a href="https://twitter.com/jr0cket/status/300151177960628224" target="_blank" rel="noopener">twitter.com/jr0cket/status/300151177960628224</a></cite></footer></blockquote>
<p>Developers arrived from different communities, including</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.meetup.com/london-scala/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">London Scala user group</a></li>
<li><a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/?fromgroups#!forum/london-clojurians" target="_blank" rel="noopener">London Clojure community</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.meetup.com/Londonjavacommunity/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">London Java Community</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.meetup.com/LondonSalesforceDevelopers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">London Salesforce developers</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.meetup.com/london-software-craftsmanship/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">London Software Craftsmanship</a>&gt;</li>
</ul>
<blockquote><p><a href="https://twitter.com/sandromancuso" title="sandromancuso" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@sandromancuso</a> Yeah our little team is awesome, I believe we’re the last ones still coding :) <a href="https://twitter.com/HackTheTower" title="HackTheTower" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@HackTheTower</a> idea is great, I truly enjoy it!</p>
<footer><strong>@balopat</strong></footer></blockquote>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="hackday" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/tags/hackday/"/>
    
      <category term="events" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/categories/events/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[MonkiGras 2013 Aftermath - Bigger, Bolder and Craftier]]></title>
    <link href="http://jr0cket.co.uk/2013/02/monkigras-2013-aftermath-bigger-bolder.html.html"/>
    <id>http://jr0cket.co.uk/2013/02/monkigras-2013-aftermath-bigger-bolder.html.html</id>
    <published>2013-02-05T11:49:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-02T20:20:15.306Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-k14DzhO7g38/TzASLJEEtpI/AAAAAAAAEa0/yHjSub8rNSg/s1600/monki-gras-2012-banner.jpg" class="img-thumbnail"> 
<p>Monki Gras conference has only just had its second outing and already its become a bit of a legend.  Its one of those conferences that is highly social and highly stimulating and also quite exhausting in a good way.  Here is some of the excitmemet I managed to capture.</p>
<a id="more"></a>
<p>Amazingly this years event only started half an hour late and was even bigger than <a href="http://jr0cket.co.uk/2012/02/monki-gras-london-craft-of-conferences.html">last year</a>.  Here are some highlights from the 2013 event.</p>
<h1 id="James-Governor-setting-the-tone"><a href="#James-Governor-setting-the-tone" class="headerlink" title="James Governor setting the tone"></a>James Governor setting the tone</h1><img src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-8gOVnx6gJWQ/UHg6D67NjrI/AAAAAAAAIYM/um3MEP7lMOM/s1600/james-govenor.jpg" class="img-thumbnail"> 
<p>In the passed, companies turned to mass production to optimise for productivity and  by consequence turned people who work in that environment into faceless drones.</p>
<p>What we need are tools and practices that support people rather than replace people.</p>
<p>As developers we have a thirst for learning how to use our tools well and how to adopt and adapt a variety of practices to improve our work.  This is now starting to become wide-spread across many other industries.</p>
<h1 id="Coffee-as-collaboration-at-Heroku"><a href="#Coffee-as-collaboration-at-Heroku" class="headerlink" title="Coffee as collaboration at Heroku"></a>Coffee as collaboration at <a href="http://www.heroku.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Heroku</a></h1><img src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5297/5396355671_d21981c6db.jpg" class="img-thumbnail">
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/craigkerstiens" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Craig Kerstiens</a> &amp; <a href="https://twitter.com/mattt" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Matt Thompson</a> - <a href="http://www.heroku.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Heroku</a></p>
<p>Some revellers enjoyed a rather liquid breakfast, for those that felt it was just a little too early for beer then it was coffee time with Heroku. </p>
<p>Matt and Craig Kerstiens talked about how the team at <a href="http://www.heroku.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Heroku</a>, the Herokai, manage to maintain the collaboration within a growing startup.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.heroku.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Heroku</a> now has 85 people, loosely organised into 21 teams.  Overall the company manages 5000 internal heroku apps and schedules 500 releases a day.  Much of the code is available in close to 200 <a href="https://github.com/organizations/heroku" target="_blank" rel="noopener">public Github repos</a>.</p>
<p>As a developer you spend a lot of time with your head down working and that limits your level of communicating.  A good balance is important for a healthy company.  Communication however is different from interruption and its well agreed fact that one interruption costs 20 minutes.  What is less well understood is that a developer gets typically 2 hours of uninterrupted working in an 8 hour day. </p>
<h2 id="So-how-do-you-encourage-communication-with-Coffee"><a href="#So-how-do-you-encourage-communication-with-Coffee" class="headerlink" title="So how do you encourage communication with Coffee?"></a>So how do you encourage communication with Coffee?</h2><p>Actually, its very hard to make a single cup of coffee at the Heroku office.  All the coffee making machines are geared up for several cups.  So you have to find someone to share coffee with you and you end up having a conversation as you are waiting.</p>
<p>Making Coffee in this way is also a great way break the ice.  Its easy to learn and as a simple craft you can show new people how to make coffee as a way of introduction to the company.  The Coffee mentioning role gives a way to demonstrate and convey some of the values of the company at the same time.</p>
<img src="http://sphotos-b.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ash4/300731_349185285162367_2128347492_n.jpg" class="img-thumbnail">
<h2 id="Headphone-rule"><a href="#Headphone-rule" class="headerlink" title="Headphone rule"></a>Headphone rule</h2><p>Its an unwritten rule in Heroku that when someone has their headphones on it means “Do not disturb”.  This allows developers to focus on their work without haviing to justify that focus to anyone else.</p>
<p>In Heroku this approch is seen as an engineers thing and sometimes others in the company dont get it at first.</p>
<h2 id="Makers-day-is-Thursday"><a href="#Makers-day-is-Thursday" class="headerlink" title="Makers day is Thursday"></a>Makers day is Thursday</h2><p>Every Thursday is sacred at Heroku and no meetings should be scheduled.  This allows engineers to easy to turn down a meeting on makers day without feeling awkward.</p>
<p>On Wednesdays Heroku have their all hands day right after lunch.  Because of this interuption, engineers typically arrange all their meetings that day.  This makes the rest of the week pretty effective for getting things done.  It also encourages others to think about the value of a meeting.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/sjmaple" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sjmaple</a> Great heroku talk! At ZeroTurnaround you’re not allowed to book meetings on Wednesday or Thursday! productivity++ #monkigras</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="Encouraging-ad-hoc-Communication"><a href="#Encouraging-ad-hoc-Communication" class="headerlink" title="Encouraging ad-hoc Communication"></a>Encouraging ad-hoc Communication</h2><p>Sometimes the best conversations happen at random, so lunch is catered every day.  As well as a great perk it also is very communal.  The dining area has a few long tables for about 12 people, helping group discussions.  The eclectic variety of food make people more willing to communicate, often asking “how do we eat this”.</p>
<p>Friday is beer day.  This is more than just drinking beer, Herokai are encouraged to suggest drinks that should be ordered.  Its also a great way to get everyone reflect on the week just gone.</p>
<h2 id="Challenges-still-remaining"><a href="#Challenges-still-remaining" class="headerlink" title="Challenges still remaining"></a>Challenges still remaining</h2><p>There is an increasing number of remote employees and maintaining regular communication is tough.</p>
<p>There is also the effect of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Allen_curve" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Allen curve</a>, which shows the exponential drop in freqnuecy of communication between engineers as the distance between them grows.</p>
<img src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-lSm0m8MOyj4/URDjKBU15UI/AAAAAAAAJAk/f1aAuDtuHdE/s1600/curva-allen-curve.png" class="img-code"> 
<p>To help everyone understand the challenges and crowd source for ideas, Heroku hold a remote week where their office is closed.  Everyone in the company works remotely, from home, on the road or out and about in their location.</p>
<p>This type of activity could also help with focusing on common tools and service consolidation.  As each team has ownership of their own practices, then tools and services have exponentially spread.  Some concensus and culling of stuff would be help communication.</p>
<h1 id="Making-for-makers"><a href="#Making-for-makers" class="headerlink" title="Making for makers"></a>Making for makers</h1><p><a href="https://twitter.com/mnowster" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mazz Mosley</a> &amp; <a href="https://twitter.com/nickstenning" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nick Stenning</a> - GDS</p>
<p>Imaging you are a craftsman with years of experience, what would happen if all of the people you dealt with were gone?  Could you imaging the emmense chain of resorces that allow you to practice your craft?</p>
<h2 id="Enter-Quantum-Physics"><a href="#Enter-Quantum-Physics" class="headerlink" title="Enter Quantum Physics"></a>Enter Quantum Physics</h2><p><a href="http://bouman.chem.georgetown.edu/general/feynman.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">I think I can safely say that nobody understands quantum mechanics - Richard P. Feynman_</a>.  There are very few people who claim to understand quantum physics, although every JavaScript programmer fundamentally relies on the principles of quantum mechanics.  Rather than make JavaScript developer spend years studying quantum physics they use <a href="http://angeleah.com/blog/2012/11/02/black-box-abstraction.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">black box abstraction</a>.</p>
<p>We have relationships with people who can do all the things we need to do our almost everything we use is an abstraction that allows us to use it effectively rather than trying to understand how its made.  The exception being soap which is a harder abstraction than the process it is supposed to encapsulate.</p>
<h2 id="Users-are-users-even-if-they-are-makers"><a href="#Users-are-users-even-if-they-are-makers" class="headerlink" title="Users are users even if they are makers."></a>Users are users even if they are makers.</h2><blockquote>
<p>Or in my words “Developers are people too” @jr0cket</p>
</blockquote>
<p>You should  understand the complexity that you pass on to your users, especially if you want to keep them!</p>
<blockquote>
<p>kenneth reitz <a href="http://kennethreitz.org/expressions/how-i-develop-things-and-why" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the user api is all that matters everything else is secondary </a></p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="Scaling-the-new-Government-website"><a href="#Scaling-the-new-Government-website" class="headerlink" title="Scaling the new Government website"></a>Scaling the new Government website</h2><img src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-ndLKp9hcA5Q/URDt3Uyc3zI/AAAAAAAAJBU/-rPdlzH2TQQ/s1600/alpha_homepage_grab.jpg" class="img-topic">
<p>In 12 weeks, a dozen people built alpha.gov.uk website from scratch to deployment and much rejoycing was had by all.</p>
<p>In 8 months, a team of 48 people built the beta version of the website.  In october 2012, the real site was launched using a team of 200 people.</p>
<p><em>So how did they scale the team in a short amount of time?</em></p>
<p>No rockstar, wizzards or ninjas were hired.  These types of developer egos all seem to drink from the ego boosting cool aid, making the same kind of mistakes as they have the same kind of attitude.  Rockstars are bullsh*t, Rockstars are not webscale!.  Rockstars are not used to listening to there users and that includes those other developers they work with every day.  A good team needs diverse set of people, to create a passionate team.</p>
<p><em>Assembling a team is a skill in its own right.</em></p>
<p>At GDS it was about hiring people who understood what the company was trying to achieve. When something is hard and not very well defined the best way to deal with this is to give it to people,  lots of diverse people who understand the goal you are working towards and have a diverse set of experiences to draw from.</p>
<p>On paper, going from alpha to beta to production in such a short time frame you need to leave your ego at the door to get stuff done</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Mazz, Uncle Bob &amp; Stan Lee: With great diversity comes great collective intelligence and power!</p>
</blockquote>
<h1 id="Scaling-happiness"><a href="#Scaling-happiness" class="headerlink" title="Scaling happiness"></a>Scaling happiness</h1><p><a href="https://twitter.com/tnm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ted Nyman</a> - Github </p>
<blockquote><p>Why do you love someone?  If you love someone for intelligence or bone structure,  then you should also love people who have even nicer examples of these things.</p>
<footer><strong>Plato</strong><cite>On Love</cite></footer></blockquote>
<img src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-10Ndc3AUd7c/URDsrM19YBI/AAAAAAAAJBI/4BC0CmkLKTg/s1600/perks-are-best-here.jpg" class="img-topic"> 
<p>Perks do not make people happy, they come and go and you cant build culture with tokens.  Token freedom perks are transitory and eventually make you wonder why a positive thing is only available a small part of the time.  If your company said you could go out in the sun for two hours once a month then you have to come inside.  You would quickly come to realise that going back inside is not where you want to be.</p>
<p>The real way you make people happy is in the organisation of the people in the company.  At Github there are no formal managers.  Cultural and technology adaptations grow naturally from this.  For example, everyone becomes part of the traditional management functions and that role becomes dispersed.  Everyone becomes responsible from hiring and ensuring people are happy.</p>
<p>If you create the structure that lets the culture form, then a culture grows to reinforces that structure.  The structure at Github being that we dont have a structure.  Everything that people need taken care of get taken care of as otherwise people complain.  Sometimes this means people doing things for themselves, or collaborating with others to get it done.</p>
<p>There are probably good managers out there, Ted just cant thing of any, well except for <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Julius_Caesar" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Julius Caesar</a>, he was a good manager!</p>
<p>The challenge remaining is that nothing actually scales, this is especially true when it comes to people.</p>
<h2 id="Summary"><a href="#Summary" class="headerlink" title="Summary"></a>Summary</h2><p>There is so much more to Monki Gras that what I managed to capture here (or would care to share in public).  The conference is really engaging and it will take a while for all the ideas and practices I experienced to peculate through my brain.</p>
<p>The evening event was amazing too, with fine food arranged to match the Craft brewed beer we were sampling.  Its a good job the conference ends on Fridays, so I could recover over the weekend.</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<img src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-k14DzhO7g38/TzASLJEEtpI/AAAAAAAAEa0/yHjSub8rNSg/s1600/monki-gras-2012-banner.jpg" class="img-thumbnail"> 
<p>Monki Gras conference has only just had its second outing and already its become a bit of a legend.  Its one of those conferences that is highly social and highly stimulating and also quite exhausting in a good way.  Here is some of the excitmemet I managed to capture.</p>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="monkigras" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/tags/monkigras/"/>
    
      <category term="events" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/categories/events/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[London Salesforce Developer Meetup - January 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://jr0cket.co.uk/2013/01/london-salesforce-developer-meetup.html.html"/>
    <id>http://jr0cket.co.uk/2013/01/london-salesforce-developer-meetup.html.html</id>
    <published>2013-01-23T20:30:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-02T20:20:15.306Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Its been a cold week in London so its great to see so many venture out to the latest meetup of the London Salesforce Developer community.</p>
<p>Thanks to our hosts, <a href="http://www.makepositive.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Make Positive</a>, there was plenty of pizza to warm everyone up and plenty of drinks to cool everyone down again.  Make positive have a very roomy office to work in and its a great space to talk to other developers and admins involved in forcedotcom projects.</p>
<a id="more"></a>
<p>We had a great talk from Rob Cowel, giving his insight into developing applications and system integrations across three cloud platforms: forcedotcom, heroku and <a href="https://www.iriscouch.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">IrisCouch</a> (CouchDB).</p>
<p>I also gave a quick update of Salesforce news, up coming events, new organisers for the community and a collection of resources for developers getting started with the force.</p>
<iframe allowfullscreen frameborder="0" height="356" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" mozallowfullscreen scrolling="no" src="http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/16138024" style="border-width: 1px 1px 0; border: 1px solid #CCC; margin-bottom: 5px;" width="427"> </iframe> 

<p><a href="http://www.slideshare.net/JR0cket/london-salesforce-developers-meetup-january-2013" title="London Salesforce Developers Meetup January 2013" target="_blank" rel="noopener">London Salesforce Developers Meetup January 2013</a> from <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/JR0cket" target="_blank" rel="noopener">John Stevenson</a></p>
<p>t of people whist not playing ping pong. As always there is a good mix of people, including Salesforce staff, the Make Postive team, developers from Tquila and many more.</p>
<p>I met a developer who has been working on a blog, <a href="http://www.cloudfollows.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">www.cloudfollows.com</a>, with others around the world aimed at those relatively new to the forcedotcom platform.  A quick glance had me very interested.  It looks a well presented site with lots of handy tips.</p>
<p>I caught up with Salesforce MVP’s Francis Pindar and Keir Bowden and they are keen to run some workshops to help people gain experience with the platform.  We’ll be running our first workshops in Tower42 on the 11th April.  There will be room for approximately 10 developers. </p>
<p>There is always so much conversation going on and I often hate to break it up for the talks.</p>
<h2 id="The-Talks"><a href="#The-Talks" class="headerlink" title="The Talks"></a>The Talks</h2><p>I  gave a quick overview of coding events we are running for the community.  This includes <strong><a href="http://jr0cket.co.uk/2013/02/hack-tower-february-2013.html">Hack the Tower</a></strong> and the upcoming coding dojo for Salesforce developers at Tquila.</p>
<p><strong>John Mahoney, Clerisoft.com</strong> gave a quick demo of Steroid, a custom components framework for the forcedotcom platform.  It provides a  library of re-usable custom components for both desktops &amp; mobile  devices.  Clerisoft developers pick ideas that are requested on … but are not planned to be added to the platform by Salesforce engineers.</p>
<p>John was looking for feedback on the concept, what components developers would find valuable and any for pepole to go try them out.</p>
<p><strong>Keir Bowden, Salesforce MVP</strong> gave a quick run  through of the <a href="http://certification.salesforce.com/Developers" target="_blank" rel="noopener">developer certification</a> process.  Each level of certification has been designed to help you grow your  skills and get great roles in industry.  Salesforce and it customers really value the certification process, as it gives a measure of confidence in the ability to deliver projects successfully.</p>
<p>Keir is also driving the  formation of the EMEA TA review board, which is a peer review process  for the top level of Salesforce developer certification.</p>
<p>Keir has now experienced the review board from the inquisitor side, being involved in the first EMEA review board. As Keir is now on the EMEA review board he is no longer in a position to offer advice on how to pass the TA certification.</p>
<p>Keir invited Chris Eales along to share his experiences, as Chris is the latest Technical Architect to pass the certification level.</p>
<h2 id="Next-months-meetup"><a href="#Next-months-meetup" class="headerlink" title="Next months meetup"></a>Next months meetup</h2><p>The next monthly meetup for the <a href="http://www.meetup.com/LondonSalesforceDevelopers/events/96135922/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">London Salesforce developers</a> is at Make Positive on the 27th March.  If you want to speak about anything please get in touch or leave a message on the meetup event. </p>
<p>Sign up at: <a href="http://www.meetup.com/LondonSalesforceDevelopers/events/96135922/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">http://www.meetup.com/LondonSalesforceDevelopers/events/96135922/</a></p>
<p>See you there.<br>Thank you.<br><a href="https://twitter.com/jr0cket" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@jr0cket</a></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Its been a cold week in London so its great to see so many venture out to the latest meetup of the London Salesforce Developer community.</p>
<p>Thanks to our hosts, <a href="http://www.makepositive.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Make Positive</a>, there was plenty of pizza to warm everyone up and plenty of drinks to cool everyone down again.  Make positive have a very roomy office to work in and its a great space to talk to other developers and admins involved in forcedotcom projects.</p>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="salesforce" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/tags/salesforce/"/>
    
      <category term="events" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/categories/events/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Heroku Hackathon for Media Industry Developers]]></title>
    <link href="http://jr0cket.co.uk/2012/11/heroku-hackathon-for-media-industry.html.html"/>
    <id>http://jr0cket.co.uk/2012/11/heroku-hackathon-for-media-industry.html.html</id>
    <published>2012-11-27T14:34:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-02T20:20:15.302Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-yIBn-HYfxeA/UI_UGVJF6AI/AAAAAAAAIdo/MLPDWYCbX2Q/s1600/heroku-logo-light-300x100.png" class="img-thumbnail"> 
<p>Bringing developers with similar experiences and interests together is a great way to organise a Hackathon.  At the latest Heroku hack, it brought together developers from media companies including the <a href="http://www.ft.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Financial Times</a>, <a href="http://www.reedbusiness.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RBI</a>, <a href="http://www.ubm.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">UBM</a>, <a href="http://www.ticketmaster.co.uk/about_us/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TicketMaster</a>, <a href="http://precursive.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Precursive</a> and <a href="http://www.tquila.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tquila</a>.</p>
<p>As this was the first event, I am very grateful to the 20 developers that braved the awful weather that day.</p>
<img src="http://rlv.zcache.co.uk/pizza_and_math_poster-r372895298c86435a8c0ee8d7e77a634c_wad_325.jpg" class="img-topic"> 
<p>The evening started with a chance for developers to “talk tech” over free beer &amp; pizza and discuss what challenges they wanted to work on that evening.  In the end we split into teams based on the main language they wanted to work in and each team worked on a different application.</p>
<p>As most of the developers were new to Heroku, went over a check-list to get started.  As <a href="http://jr0cket.co.uk/2012/11/git-push-deploy-7-tiny-steps-to.html">its so easy to use Heroku</a> then this only took a couple of minutes.</p>
<p>Thanks to the developers at Salesforce, we also had a “Heroku mentor” for each team to help them get going.  Once everyone was over the initial steps with Heroku, the only challenging part was to work together to build their application in a short space of time.</p>
<h1 id="Getting-creative-with-Application-Development"><a href="#Getting-creative-with-Application-Development" class="headerlink" title="Getting creative with Application Development"></a>Getting creative with Application Development</h1><p>The different teams chose to develop applications with Java, Ruby and Node.js.</p>
<img src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-I-r6IgSu_Wg/ULTOqpFhSbI/AAAAAAAAInI/OL8mLfGIR10/s1600/heroku-postgress-addon.png" class="img-topic"> One team was quite ambitions in trying to build a location based app for seeing where the most popular tweets were coming from.  Using <a href="https://addons.heroku.com/catalog/heroku-postgresql" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Heroku Postgres</a> they quickly extracted the data they needed.  The location information would be shown using Google maps and unfortunately they introduced a bug they didn’t quite fix in in time that stopped those locations showing up as pins on the map.<br><br>One developer also succeeded in deploying something he had written previously, a graphical to-do list.  Although it was a fairly static HTML &amp; JavaScript site, by changing the index.html file to index.php then Heroku was happy to run it as an application.<br><br><img src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-PwP7CDcQ1ng/ULTOBOu1EmI/AAAAAAAAInA/cFr17ApxCvI/s1600/heroku-create-and-push.png" class="img-code"> 
<p>The other teams created a voting application and an “all I want for christmas” wish list, similar to Amazon. </p>
<p>So every team got something deployed live to the Internet, some teams even got more than one app live!</p>
<p>The hackathons go on and the next one will be an all day <a href="http://www.meetup.com/LondonSalesforceDevelopers/events/91343352/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hack the Tower</a> at one of the tallest buildings in London, Tower 42.  Salesforce has an office with amazing views and we 50 developers signed up across different technical communities.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Update: December 2013 - HackTheTower has now moved to the Salesforce Tower in London, previously known as the Heron tower.</p>
</blockquote>
<h1 id="Back-to-basics"><a href="#Back-to-basics" class="headerlink" title="Back to basics"></a>Back to basics</h1><img src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-89_7BGHfAIc/ULTNeODtOcI/AAAAAAAAIm4/KAzHL6savLs/s1600/heroku-continuous-deliver-enterprise.png" class="img-code"> 
<p>By popular demand, I’m also planning some Heroku workshops at Tower42 (where I am also running “Hack the Tower”).  These workshops will give developers the experience needed to help them deploying their apps naturally and give them an effective deployment workflow with other common tools such as Github.</p>
<p>The workshops will also give developers insight into how they can learn other cool technology such as MongoDB &amp; Redis without the hassle of installation and configuration. </p>
<blockquote>
<p>Sign up for free to the <a href="http://www.meetup.com/LondonSalesforceDevelopers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">London Salesforce Developer community</a> to keep up with these events.I am also planning a talk for the <a href="http://www.meetup.com/Londonjavacommunity/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">London Java Community</a> (3,000 members) on “Heroku for Java Developers”.  This will help give developers a good overview of the platform capabilities, the developer workflow &amp; tools as well as add-ons and cool technology they can easily try out.  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Thank you.<br><a href="https://twitter.com/jr0cket" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@jr0cket</a></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<img src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-yIBn-HYfxeA/UI_UGVJF6AI/AAAAAAAAIdo/MLPDWYCbX2Q/s1600/heroku-logo-light-300x100.png" class="img-thumbnai]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="heroku" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/tags/heroku/"/>
    
      <category term="hackathon" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/tags/hackathon/"/>
    
      <category term="events" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/categories/events/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[All Your Base Aftermath - the Afternoon]]></title>
    <link href="http://jr0cket.co.uk/2012/11/all-your-base-aftermath-afternoon.html.html"/>
    <id>http://jr0cket.co.uk/2012/11/all-your-base-aftermath-afternoon.html.html</id>
    <published>2012-11-23T16:37:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-02T20:20:15.290Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-mf5oQ5REbLA/UK_KqBKfA9I/AAAAAAAAIlg/NkVH_v20CLM/s1600/all_your_base_conf_2012.png" class="img-thumbnail"> 
<p>The second half of All your base was just as great as the first, although there was so many interesting ideas and new shiny things to try I will be busy through the holidays trying to process it all.</p>
<p>The talks this in the afternoon treated us to a feast of: Git as a NoSQL db, Redis, MySQL at Twitter, LawnChair mobile web persistence, Postgres Demystified and Apache Cassandra.  What follows is just some of that data goodness…</p>
<a id="more"></a>
<h1 id="Postgres-Demystified-by-Craig-Kerstiens-Heroku"><a href="#Postgres-Demystified-by-Craig-Kerstiens-Heroku" class="headerlink" title="Postgres Demystified by Craig Kerstiens, Heroku"></a>Postgres Demystified by Craig Kerstiens, Heroku</h1><p><a href="https://speakerdeck.com/craigkerstiens/postgres-demystified" target="_blank" rel="noopener">slides</a>)</p>
<p><a href="http://www.postgresql.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Postgres</a> is a really powerful database yet still feels pretty lightweight to use and a world away from the heavy-duty admin required for other “enterprise” db’s.</p>
<p>Postgres is also one of the most innovative relational datbases out there, long having an object-relational model and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multiversion_concurrency_control" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Multiversion Concurrency Control</a> (MVCC) to keep data really safe.  Support was recently added for storing data in the <a href="http://json.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">json</a> format and you can even hook Postgrest up directly to <a href="http://redis.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Redis</a>.</p>
<p>With so many features it often referred to as the <strong>emacs of databases</strong>, in that it can really do so much more than most databases.</p>
<p>So its no surprise then that the popularity of Postgres has grown over the last few years and that companies such as Atlassian and Heroku run their businesses on it.</p>
<img src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-Nsye5ICWkTY/ULzEtFbtc2I/AAAAAAAAInk/Pv7TAovtJd0/s1600/mac-boo-pro-sideon-lid-closing.jpg" class="img-topic"> 
<p>One bug-bear for developers was trying to get postgres installed on a Mac, it was far too painful.  So the team at Heroku created an app for that at <a href="http://postgresapp.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">http://postgresapp.com/</a>.  Now its just a matter of a download and dragging the .app to your applications folder.</p>
<p>Otherwise, PSQL is a really easy to use terminal client for Postgres. PSQL enabling you to execute queries interactively and see the query results instantly.  PSQL also supports tab completes and <code>\e</code> allows you to edit the commands directly in what ever is your default shell editor (emacs, vim, etc).  PSQL also provides meta-commands and various shell-like features to facilitate writing scripts and automating a wide variety of tasks, so its really flexible.</p>
<p>There are lots of data types supported in Postgres, including the really useful <em>arrays</em>.  As thought has been put into time based data then support for Range types and <code>timestamptz</code> is also a really so nice touch to help you prevent time conflicts.</p>
<p>Postgres 9.2 brings direct support for <a href="http://json.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">json</a> data type.  Coupling this with the JavaScript V8 engine that is now part of the database server you can do some very powerful things.  However, instead of just SQL injection attacks to be  wary about, it you dont manage access to your database carefully, you  could also be susceptible to json and javascript injection attacks - so use with care. </p>
<blockquote>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/lizconlan" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@lizconlan</a> Great Postgres primer from <a href="http://twitter.com/craigkerstiens" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@craigkerstiens</a>, totally get the emacs quote <a href="http://twitter.com/AYBconf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">#AYBconf</a></p>
</blockquote>
<h1 id="Performance-tips"><a href="#Performance-tips" class="headerlink" title="Performance tips"></a>Performance tips</h1><p>Using the <code>explain</code> command can help you work out inefficiencies in your database queries.  Adding explain to your queries will show you what is going to happen if that query is run and an estimate of how long postgres thinks it will take to run.</p>
<p>Using <code>explain analyze</code> postgres will run the query and then analyse how long the query actually took.  A good target is to aim for 10 miliseconds as a baseline.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.pgadmin.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PgAdmin</a> can also show you a graphical representation of the explain plan.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/craigkerstiens" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@craigkerstiens</a> your web app DB query should take 10ms at most <a href="https://twitter.com/AYBConf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@AYBConf</a> <a href="http://tweetchat.com/room/ayb12" target="_blank" rel="noopener">#ayb12</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>A great indexing technique is to create your indexes concurrenty, so you dont need to take you database off for a day to improve performance.</p>
<pre><code>create index concurrently _index_name_ on _table_ 
</code></pre><p>However, dont worry about indexes too much up front, wait and see how your uses work with your application and then start to optimise.</p>
<p>There are lots more <strong><a href="http://www.craigkerstiens.com/2012/04/30/why-postgres/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reasons to use Postgres</a></strong>, as covered in a blog series by Craig.  You can also discover more detail about postgres with <a href="http://www.postgresguide.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Craigs online guide</a>.</p>
<p>Get a jump start by <strong><a href="https://addons.heroku.com/heroku-postgresql" target="_blank" rel="noopener">adding postgres to your application on Heroku</a></strong> or get <strong><a href="https://postgres.heroku.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Postgress as a service</a></strong>.</p>
<h1 id="Git-the-NoSQL-database"><a href="#Git-the-NoSQL-database" class="headerlink" title="Git - the NoSQL database ?"></a>Git - the NoSQL database ?</h1><p>We all know that Git is amazing at storing and managing source code, but how is it for data?  That was the question posed by Brandon Keepers of Github?</p>
<blockquote>
<p><a href="http://twitter.com/alegonbel" target="_blank" rel="noopener">alegonbel</a> Git = the stupid content tracker <a href="https://twitter.com/ayb12" target="_blank" rel="noopener">#ayb12</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>When you ask git what it is, <code>man git</code>, then it just tells you its a stupid content tracker.  That doesnt mean its a bad tracker, its just that it does not care what it is tracking, leading to the idea that Git can be used for more than code.</p>
<img src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-uPeHmICWqLM/UK_FbuqEBhI/AAAAAAAAIlI/R7hBrt5F4hU/s1600/git-man-stupid-content-tracker.png" class="img-topic">
<p>If you look at the contents of the <code>.git/objects</code> folder for a project you can see all the files that make up the git data model.  So you can see, its not like a “traditional” data store and as its file based will have several limitations.</p>
<img src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-A4LlPh6PMrM/UK_LcVJkdTI/AAAAAAAAIlo/Wm2PnNTMd3E/s1600/git-internals-commits.png" class="img-code"> 
<p>When a file is added to git, <code>git add</code>, <code>git commit</code>, it puts that file in a blob and creates a hash of the data that is therefore unique.  If the hash is the same on two files it means that their data is exactly the same.</p>
<p>A tree is then created that points to that blob and any other related trees.  Finally we get back to a commit, which has a tree that is the root of the project as well as project info such as author and message.</p>
<p>When a new change is added to git it has to point to a point in the existing tree.  As anything existing is immutable, a new file is created as a blob with a new tree that points to.  However, that new tree can use reference a parent in the existing tree so changes are added efficiently as only the things that have changed are added to the data model.</p>
<p>All the great features that database systems have, git has none of those.  What git can do is:</p>
<ul>
<li>Versioning - look back at previous changes really easily and create diffs of what has changed.</li>
<li>Hooks - update caches as an alternative form of indexing for searches.</li>
<li>No “big design up front” - optimize the storage based on the actual usage patterns and evolve the data structures as more discovery is made.</li>
<li>Branches - gives long lived transactions</li>
<li>Replication - a clone is a full copy of all the data and clones can be driven by hooks So Querying data is something you just have to figure out yourself.  Concurrency is a challenge as git is file system based, so when multiple people try to update then changes could be lost.  Scaling is also a really big challenge, especially when randomly updating records in git - partly this is because we are re-writing the whole tree structure to make an update.</li>
</ul>
<p>Git also does a really bad job when it comes to handling long running projects that have grown considerable in size.  Add, status and commit commands talke longer and longer. </p>
<p>So whilst its interesting to think about git as some kind of simple data store, there are a great many challenges if you want to manage big data sets within one git project. </p>
<p>Brandon left us with the thought <em>“abuse your tools, imagine how to make them better!”</em>.</p>
<h1 id="Redis-Steady-Go"><a href="#Redis-Steady-Go" class="headerlink" title="Redis Steady Go"></a>Redis Steady Go</h1><img src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-nDtNvipmj1g/ULACYq-_CDI/AAAAAAAAImI/8zQu6eoIM5I/s1600/redis-logo-300dpi.png" class="img-topic"> 
<blockquote>
<p>Redis is one of those great projects that when discovered by developers they really take to it.  Redis is short for <em>remote dictionary server</em> although you can think of it as a <em>remote hashing server</em>.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Put simply it manages strings that are keys and values.  It is often referred to as a <em>data structure server</em> since keys can contain <a href="http://redis.io/topics/data-types#strings" target="_blank" rel="noopener">strings</a>, <a href="http://redis.io/topics/data-types#hashes" target="_blank" rel="noopener">hashes</a>, <a href="http://redis.io/topics/data-types#lists" target="_blank" rel="noopener">lists</a>, <a href="http://redis.io/topics/data-types#sets" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sets</a> and <a href="http://redis.io/topics/data-types#sorted-sets" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sorted sets</a>. </p>
<p>You can also consider redis as a Domain Specific Language (DSL) for abstract data types.  Its similar to memcache but it adds a whole lot more functionality.</p>
<p>There are three big uses for Redis:</p>
<ul>
<li>A simple to use and work with NoSQL database</li>
<li>A messaging system, Redis comes with a publish / subscribe API</li>
<li>A web application cache (an alternative to memcache) - you can store your webpages in redis and they come out really fastSony use redis to manage the scoring from their online Playstation3 games network. Using a sorted set in Redis, millions of scores are managed for each game (as I can attest to on my poor scoring when playing StarDust).    </li>
</ul>
<p>Pintrest also used redis as much of their content, specifically as they presented their content in terms of ranking.  All those values of all those users have to be kept somewhere.</p>
<p>Some important characteristics of Redis include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Individual actions are atomic so data does not become corrupt</li>
<li>Single threaded</li>
<li>Event driven</li>
<li>Data can be expired</li>
<li>Replication can be done with the use of a slave and Redis is very good at live replacement.</li>
<li>Very high performance - everything is stored in memory, so its super fast.  It does have persistence though as otherwise it wouldn’t be ultimately useful.</li>
<li>You can use just about any language you have ever heard of with Redis (except <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Assembly_language" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Assembly</a> &amp; <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fortran" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fortran</a>).</li>
<li>You can also use Redis from the Postgres databaseSo what are you waiting for, go and play with <a href="http://redis.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Redis</a> today!  Or simply add <a href="https://addons.heroku.com/catalog/redistogo" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RedisToGo</a> to your application on Heroku</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="In-Summary"><a href="#In-Summary" class="headerlink" title="In Summary"></a>In Summary</h1><p>All your base was a fantastic experience and its great to see how hugely popular conferences are.  It was great to mix with people from a wider range of backgrounds that the usual developer conference.</p>
<p>I am looking forward to All Your Base 2013!</p>
<p>Thank you.<br><a href="https://twitter.com/jr0cket" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@jr0cket</a></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<img src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-mf5oQ5REbLA/UK_KqBKfA9I/AAAAAAAAIlg/NkVH_v20CLM/s1600/all_your_base_conf_2012.png" class="img-thumbnail"> 
<p>The second half of All your base was just as great as the first, although there was so many interesting ideas and new shiny things to try I will be busy through the holidays trying to process it all.</p>
<p>The talks this in the afternoon treated us to a feast of: Git as a NoSQL db, Redis, MySQL at Twitter, LawnChair mobile web persistence, Postgres Demystified and Apache Cassandra.  What follows is just some of that data goodness…</p>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="events" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/categories/events/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[All Your Base Aftermath - Morning Round Up]]></title>
    <link href="http://jr0cket.co.uk/2012/11/all-your-base-aftermath-morning-round-up.html.html"/>
    <id>http://jr0cket.co.uk/2012/11/all-your-base-aftermath-morning-round-up.html.html</id>
    <published>2012-11-23T12:57:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-02T20:20:15.290Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.whiteoctober.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/all_your_base_conf_2012.png" class="img-thumbnails">
<p>The <em>All Your Base conference</em> was a brilliant example of getting a  conference right.  Everything was ideal.  The venue was right next to the train station and the after party was directly opposite, so staggering for the trainback home.</p>
<p>The network was awesome, actually getting a hard line and even a free ethernet cable in the goody bag (because who is going to remember to bring one). </p>
<p>And of course an amazing line up of speakers from cool companies including MongoDB (10gen), Heroku, Basho, MariaDB and many more.</p>
<p>Here is part one of my experiences at All Your Base.</p>
<a id="more"></a>
<h1 id="Dynamic-data-with-MongoDB"><a href="#Dynamic-data-with-MongoDB" class="headerlink" title="Dynamic data with MongoDB"></a>Dynamic data with MongoDB</h1><img src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-URYGwZsN2CE/UK9qDsMTWdI/AAAAAAAAIj4/33Ne75f399c/s1600/mongo-db-logo.png" class="img-thumbnails"> 
<p>Alvin Richards gave a great peek under the skirt of MongoDB, discussing replication, latency and how to manage data effectively in a distributed system.  Some classic authors used for the JSon examples that define the mongodb “schema”.  I say schema, but MongoDB does not require an up-front schema design like a relational database.  All you need is a unique key and you can manage your data in what ever way you want using the flexible data document approach.  This allows you to have <em>polymorphic data</em>, in that you can assemble data in the way that suits your application rather than being constrained by the database product.</p>
<p>With all this power over the data, comes great responsibility.  It shouldn’t just be a “Wild West” approach.  So good conversations are important between developers and database admins. </p>
<blockquote>
<p>Find out more about MongoDB by <a href="http://www.mongodb.org/display/DOCS/Community" target="_blank" rel="noopener">getting involved in the community</a>.  And try out MongoDB with your application by using the add-on available via Heroku.</p>
</blockquote>
<h1 id="NoSQL-answer-to-managing-complex-domains"><a href="#NoSQL-answer-to-managing-complex-domains" class="headerlink" title="NoSQL answer to managing complex domains"></a>NoSQL answer to managing complex domains</h1><img src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-57wTz697UCU/UK9yko6i49I/AAAAAAAAIkY/PDaHj-PYu0Y/s1600/OrientdbLogo.png" class="img-topic">
<p>Graph databases are already used widely in the “friend-of-a-friend” networks like LinkedIn, although are generally new to the audience at the conference.</p>
<p>With a graph database you can have multiple connections between data creating a very intricate strcutre.  So whilst the graph concept is very simple, there is much to learn about using graph database well.</p>
<p>In a relational model, its important to focus on the design of the data relationships.  The more complexity the data relationships, the more complexity in the design of the database.  The biggest hangover from complex relational database design is the join.  If you traverse hundres of relationships then you are executing hundreds of JOINs.</p>
<p>The more joins you have to process the more your performance will be affected and the relational model computes that relationship every time you query the database.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A graph database is any storage system that provides index-free adjacency - Marko RodriguezOrientDB is an open source (Apache licence) document graph nosql dbms - supports transactions, etenended,  ACID Transactions, SQL and Native Queries, Asynchronous Commands, Intents, etc.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>GraphDB handels relationships as a physical Link to the record assigned when the edige is created, so traversing cost is no longer affected by db size.  Eg, traversing 30milion connections in 5 seconds </p>
<p>Once you have a well connencted DB in the for of a Super Graph, you can cross records instead of query them.  All you need is some <strong>root verticies</strong> to start traversing.</p>
<h1 id="PouchDB-because-Offline-data-is-still-the-reality"><a href="#PouchDB-because-Offline-data-is-still-the-reality" class="headerlink" title="PouchDB because Offline data is still the reality"></a>PouchDB because Offline data is still the reality</h1><p>Voted by the WhiteOctober developers as the most interesting technology they wanted to see, Dale Harvey the creator of <a href="http://pouchdb.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PouchDB</a> gave a great presentation using HTML5 slides (nice).  Dale currently works on Firefox OS for Mozilla and is a CouchDB contributor, so he knows what he is talking about.</p>
<p>Essentially, PouchDB is CouchDB for your browser.  You can use it by including the pouchdb.js script in your web code with a simple <code>&lt;script&gt;</code> directive.<br><code>&lt;script src=pouchdb.js&gt; &lt;/script&gt;</code> </p>
<p>Like all flexible tools, PouchDB uses JSon as the primary data store.  This gives you a great amount of flexibility in the design and use of your data.</p>
<p>Under the hood, <a href="http://pouchdb.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PouchDB</a> uses indexedDB when run in IE, firefox, chrome.  For nodejs it uses leveldb.</p>
<p>Why is <a href="http://pouchdb.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PouchDB</a> here, well according to Dave - <em>Multi Master replication is awesome</em></p>
<p>If you have an app and you want to work offline then this <a href="http://pouchdb.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PouchDB</a> is a great idea.  I wish something like this was part of GoogleDocs so I could continue to edit documents when I loose connection to the Internet.  There are also many other mobile use cases where you need the data locally, not just because of limited connectivity but also for speed.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><a href="http://twitter.com/jr0cket" target="_blank" rel="noopener">jr0cket</a> Offline is still a fact - people still need some data locally especially when on the move</p>
</blockquote>
<p>So what’s wrong with building an active sync into your app?  Well it is very challenging.  Sync’ing is very hard, especially when it comes to conflict resolution.  <a href="http://pouchdb.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PouchDB</a> provides a very simple mechanism to handle it.  Every document is referenced by a single id, if you change the document name then is still knows its the same document.  Only when you change the id of the document does it become a different doc.  </p>
<p>Different changes are saved separately so it allow you to merge conflicts through the PouchDB API.</p>
<p>This sounds like something I’d like to include in mobile projects, so hope to get some time to play with <a href="http://pouchdb.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PouchDB</a> over the holidays.</p>
<h1 id="Michael-“Monty”-Widenius-Creator-of-MySQL-and-MariaDB"><a href="#Michael-“Monty”-Widenius-Creator-of-MySQL-and-MariaDB" class="headerlink" title="Michael “Monty” Widenius - Creator of MySQL and MariaDB"></a>Michael “Monty” Widenius - Creator of MySQL and MariaDB</h1><img src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ArH-Zpu89eU/UK9wEsiBnUI/AAAAAAAAIkQ/Sx3BeaI8KTs/s1600/mariadb-seal-flat-browntext-413x129-93172cc5c273985596a8dca78e58aa49370c4bed.png" class="img-topic"> 
<p>The MySQL project started from a desire to help people and do lots of travelling.  After MySQL was aquired by Sun (and before aquired by Oracle) new life was breathed into the open source project.  The original creators behind MySQL shifted to start working on <a href="https://mariadb.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MariaDB</a>, a community developed database with more features yet still compatible with MySQL.</p>
<p>There is no reason to use MySQL anymore, <a href="https://mariadb.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MariaDB</a> is better in every respect.  Its completely open and all the closed source features added to MySQL has been added to MariaDB already.  It seems that Oracle has lost much of the engineering talent around MySQL and is not able to do much around the product, hence the closed source add-ons. </p>
<blockquote>
<p><a href="http://twitter.com/mark_star" target="_blank" rel="noopener">mark_star</a> “MariaDb is better than MySQL in every way” - Monty, the creator of MySQL <a href="http://tweetchat.com/room/betterMigrate" target="_blank" rel="noopener">#betterMigrate</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>One goal of <a href="https://mariadb.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MariaDB</a> is to make a bridge between Relational and NoSQL models.  Using a concept called Dynamic Columns, a proof of concept of this was done by creating a storage engine for Cassandra. </p>
<p>When you want to make MySQL obsolute (which is what Monty does) then you have to provide something better to replace it.  In all respects it seems that is what the MariaDB project has achieved.  From additional in features, major performance improvements, community support and documentation then MariaDB has already become a valuable successor.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><a href="http://twitter.com/ciderpunx" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ciderpunx)</a> Cool I’ve now got <a href="https://twitter.com/MariaDB" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@MariaDB</a> installed and working. All my MySQL DBs intact </p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p><a href="http://twitter.com/montywi" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@montywi</a> Try MariaDB for yourself, it will take you less than 15 seconds to migrate, depending on how fast you type.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Break for lunch… see you soon.</p>
<p>Thank you.<br><a href="https://twitter.com/jr0cket" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@jr0cket</a></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<img src="http://www.whiteoctober.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/all_your_base_conf_2012.png" class="img-thumbnails">
<p>The <em>All Your Base conference</em> was a brilliant example of getting a  conference right.  Everything was ideal.  The venue was right next to the train station and the after party was directly opposite, so staggering for the trainback home.</p>
<p>The network was awesome, actually getting a hard line and even a free ethernet cable in the goody bag (because who is going to remember to bring one). </p>
<p>And of course an amazing line up of speakers from cool companies including MongoDB (10gen), Heroku, Basho, MariaDB and many more.</p>
<p>Here is part one of my experiences at All Your Base.</p>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="events" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/categories/events/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The Master Plan for Salesforce Community Developers]]></title>
    <link href="http://jr0cket.co.uk/2012/11/the-master-plan-for-salesforce.html.html"/>
    <id>http://jr0cket.co.uk/2012/11/the-master-plan-for-salesforce.html.html</id>
    <published>2012-11-15T18:21:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-02T20:20:15.306Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-2YtIbrYxq-A/UKUmQSaEeZI/AAAAAAAAIig/N7P66eyzdhs/s1600/salesforce-devzone-800k-devs.png" class="img-thumbnail">
<p>The promise of fast application development using the Salesforce platform is very appealing and the latest release has attracted over 800,000 developers.</p>
<p><a href="http://heroku.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Heroku</a> (part of the Salesforce family) is also attracting a lot of attention.  By allowing developers to deploy their applications with a simple <code>git push</code> command, it helps make continuous deployment becomes a reality.</p>
<p>These  are just two of the reasons I took the opportunity to join the  amazing team at salesforce.com.  So you can imagine I was overjoyed when I  started as Developer Advocate for EMEA.  Here is what that role is all  about.</p>
<a id="more"></a>
<h1 id="The-Plan"><a href="#The-Plan" class="headerlink" title="The Plan"></a>The Plan</h1><img src="http://blogs.developerforce.com/developer-relations/files/2012/11/the-master-plan.png" class="img-thumbnail">
<p>The plan is simple.  Help developers understand the value of developing applications with the force.com platform as well as the benefits of using Heroku to deploy their other application and services.</p>
<p>Starting with the UK, I am working hard to pull the current Salesforce developers together and build a strong community.  I’m also helping developers new to the platform to get a solid understanding of where they can use these platforms for their companies benefit and their own.</p>
<h1 id="Building-the-community"><a href="#Building-the-community" class="headerlink" title="Building the community"></a>Building the community</h1><p>(% img img-thumbnail <a href="http://blogs.developerforce.com/developer-relations/files/2012/11/meetup-logo.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">http://blogs.developerforce.com/developer-relations/files/2012/11/meetup-logo.jpg</a> %}</p>
<p>One of our partners, <a href="http://www.tquila.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tquila</a>, did a great job of starting a <a href="http://www.meetup.com/LondonSalesforceDevelopers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Salesforce developer community in London</a>.   I have aims of making it this community more active.  In the last month we have seen a 300% rise in members and I hope we can keep growing with exciting <a href="http://www.meetup.com/LondonSalesforceDevelopers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">events</a> in the coming months.</p>
<p>I am also looking for a few passionate geeks to start communities in  their own areas. Its pretty easy to get started and salesforce.com will create a meetup.com site for you so other developers can find your  events.  Those events dont have to be grand, it can all start with a meetup in a pub (like the developer meetups in <a href="http://www.meetup.com/Bristol-Salesforce-Platform-Developer-User-Group/events/88044102/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bristol</a> &amp; <a href="http://www.meetup.com/North-UK-Salesforce-Developer-User-Group/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Leeds</a>).  It just needs someone to kick-start it all and you will soon have a thriving community.</p>
<p>Check to see if there is a <a href="https://maps.google.com/maps/ms?msid=210108725500451274783.0004cab36a064aa71872b&amp;msa=0&amp;ll=39.639538,0.527344&amp;spn=108.01067,270.527344" title="Salesforce user groups world wide" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Salesforce community in your area</a> and get involved to boost your career - and have some fun too!  If there is no group in your area, why not <a href="mailto:info@developerforce.com" title="mailto:info@developerforce.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">contact us</a> and we’ll help you start one?</p>
<h1 id="Bringing-developers-together"><a href="#Bringing-developers-together" class="headerlink" title="Bringing developers together"></a>Bringing developers together</h1><p>People can always do so much more with the help of others.  I see the community as an amazing place to learn, discover and share ideas and techniques with open minded developers.</p>
<p>Through the local Salesforce communities we are building across Europe, we will be running lots of different events.  Here are some we are lining up already.</p>
<h2 id="Hack-the-Tower-getting-practical"><a href="#Hack-the-Tower-getting-practical" class="headerlink" title="Hack the Tower - getting practical"></a><a href="http://hackthetower.co.uk" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hack the Tower</a> - getting practical</h2><p>There is so much more you can discover by getting a group of developers  together and putting together an application in the space of a few hours.  I recently supported the <a href="http://blog.jr0cket.co.uk/2012/10/london-scala-hackathon-powered-by-heroku.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">London Scala hackathon</a> where we used Heroku, Github, Play framework and MongoDB to build a community website in a morning.</p>
<img src="http://developer.salesforce.com/blogs/developer-relations/files/2012/11/LSug-hackathon-hackers-hacking.png" class="img-code">
<p>Another variation is to bring developers together from the same industry.  Not  only will these developers face similar challenges when building  applications, they can work with each other to build services that  benefit the industry.  Our first mini-hack is with <a href="http://www.meetup.com/LondonSalesforceDevelopers/events/86354442/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">developers in the media industry on 21st November</a>.</p>
<p>Using our space in <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?q=Level+27A%2C+25+Old+Broad+Street%2C+London.+EC2N+1HQ+%2C+London" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tower42</a> not only gives amazing views of London but allows  us to running a series of hackathons for the many developer communities  around London.  Our first “<a href="http://www.meetup.com/LondonSalesforceDevelopers/events/91343352/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">HackTheTower</a>“ on the 8th December in conjunction with the <a href="http://www.meetup.com/london-scala/events/91346712/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">London Scala user group</a>.</p>
<h2 id="Developer-Days"><a href="#Developer-Days" class="headerlink" title="Developer Days"></a>Developer Days</h2><p>There are some amazing things you can do with the <a href="http://developer.salesforce.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Salesforce1 Platform</a> and <a href="http://www.heroku.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Heroku</a> platform.  To learn all these can take a bit of time and so to help  those new to the platforms we are planning “developer days” to  kick-start your journey.</p>
<p>The developer days will consist of a morning of discussion to help you understand the <a href="http://developer.force.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Force.com</a> and <a href="http://www.heroku.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Heroku</a> platforms.  Then you  spend the whole afternoon building applications, practising what you have learnt with guidance from our on-site experts.</p>
<p>The developer days will run across Europe in the coming months (<em>update: these are now called Elevate</em>).</p>
<h1 id="Who-am-I"><a href="#Who-am-I" class="headerlink" title="Who am I?"></a>Who am I?</h1><p>My background is mainly in Java development, although I have also done JavaScript, Python, Ruby and .Net apps too.  Recently I have been learning functional programming with Clojure (and Emacs) and <a href="http://clojuremadesimple.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">teaching what I have learnt</a> to others.</p>
<p>I love learning <a href="http://clojure.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Clojure</a> because its  an amazing new (and old) language and its great to deploy my Clojure web  apps on Heroku.  I also give talks and run practical sessions for Clojure, Java, Scala and other technical communities across the UK.</p>
<p>I have been lucky to work with some great companies in my time.  They  including Atlassian, several start-ups in London and several consultancy companies (mainly financial services) across the UK and Europe.</p>
<p>Talking tech is great fun and I love discussing all the possibilities out there.  Hope to meet you at a community event soon!</p>
<p>Thank you.<br><a href="http://twitter.com/jr0cket" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@jr0cket</a></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<img src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-2YtIbrYxq-A/UKUmQSaEeZI/AAAAAAAAIig/N7P66eyzdhs/s1600/salesforce-devzone-800k-devs.png" class="img-thumbnail">
<p>The promise of fast application development using the Salesforce platform is very appealing and the latest release has attracted over 800,000 developers.</p>
<p><a href="http://heroku.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Heroku</a> (part of the Salesforce family) is also attracting a lot of attention.  By allowing developers to deploy their applications with a simple <code>git push</code> command, it helps make continuous deployment becomes a reality.</p>
<p>These  are just two of the reasons I took the opportunity to join the  amazing team at salesforce.com.  So you can imagine I was overjoyed when I  started as Developer Advocate for EMEA.  Here is what that role is all  about.</p>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="salesforce" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/tags/salesforce/"/>
    
      <category term="events" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/categories/events/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Developer Mentors Invade Kings College London]]></title>
    <link href="http://jr0cket.co.uk/2012/11/developer-mentors-invade-kings-college_1.html.html"/>
    <id>http://jr0cket.co.uk/2012/11/developer-mentors-invade-kings-college_1.html.html</id>
    <published>2012-11-01T15:14:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-02T20:20:15.298Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-aqvkk1hXMKs/UJKPf9DH41I/AAAAAAAAIfA/6nRGAqOmupI/s1600/gdc-logo.jpg" class="img-thumbnail">
<p>It was great to meet so many eager minds at Kings College during the Meet a Mentor session for the Graduate Developer community.</p>
<p>Kings College is a stunning setting for helping students understand the expectations that will be put upon them when they get into industry.</p>
<a id="more"></a>
<h1 id="The-approach"><a href="#The-approach" class="headerlink" title="The approach"></a>The approach</h1><p>In the same approach as speed-dating and speed-flatsharing, the Meet a memtor evening has a number of tables of students and the mentors have 15 minutes to introduce themselves and answer questions.</p>
<p>Normally we pair mentors per table, however there was such a demand  this time at Kings College, each table had one mentor at a time.&nbsp; The  tables had around 50 students distributed evenly over them.</p>
<p>Every mentor has a different background, this isnt by design its just that most people in the IT industry have a very unique set of experiences.&nbsp; Even if the students are asking the same questions over again then they get different answers.</p>
<h1 id="The-podcast"><a href="#The-podcast" class="headerlink" title="The podcast"></a>The podcast</h1><p>We had request from the GDC members to record the Meet the Mentor sessions.&nbsp; I was a bit skeptical on how well this would work.&nbsp; I had my second session recorded, where I talk about the pros and cons of working as a consultant, how much I dislike PHP and whether understanding performance really matters.</p>
<img src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-EYkurLAE9AQ/TunyfGld5oI/AAAAAAAAIdQ/Gl9QfYaSXWY/s1600/john-stevenson-profile-barrel.png" class="img-topic"> 
<p>Listen to the session and find out for yourself if you think recording these sessions are useful</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><br><div><object align="middle" classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" codebase="http://fpdownload.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,0,0" height="25" id="mp3playerlightsmallv3" width="210"> <param name="allowScriptAccess" value="sameDomain"> <param name="movie" value="http://www.podbean.com/podcast-audio-video-blog-player/mp3playerlightsmallv3.swf?audioPath=http://recworks.podbean.com/mf/play/rk2pa/MaM30_10B.mp3&autoStart=no"> <param name="quality" value="high"><param name="bgcolor" value="#ffffff"><param name="wmode" value="transparent"> <embed src="http://www.podbean.com/podcast-audio-video-blog-player/mp3playerlightsmallv3.swf?audioPath=http://recworks.podbean.com/mf/play/rk2pa/MaM30_10B.mp3&autoStart=no" quality="high" width="210" height="25" name="mp3playerlightsmallv3" align="middle" allowscriptaccess="sameDomain" wmode="transparent" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" pluginspage="http://www.macromedia.com/go/getflashplayer"> </object><br><a href="http://www.podbean.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Podcast Powered By Podbean</a> </div><br></div>

<p>I have been told that I talk more than the other mentors, but do well to engage with everyone on the table.&nbsp; The best way to stop me taking is to ask more questions.</p>
<h1 id="Common-Questions"><a href="#Common-Questions" class="headerlink" title="Common Questions"></a>Common Questions</h1><p>Having been a mentor at many of these events, there are common questions that the students ask and we have run specific sessions in the past to cover topics such as open source projects and developer tools. </p>
<iframe src="http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/14982333" width="100%" height="300" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<p><a href="http://www.slideshare.net/JR0cket/improve-your-development-skills-with-test-driven-development" title="Improve your development skills with Test Driven Development" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Improve your development skills with Test Driven Development</a> from <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/jr0cket" target="_blank" rel="noopener">John Stevenson</a></p>
<p>This limited experience with  common development tools and practices is something that is very prevelent when developers go for their first role.&nbsp; It would be great to get some blog posts tackling these common gaps with opinions from the  mentors and others in the community.</p>
<ul>
<li>How to get into an open source project - its easier than you think</li>
<li>How to boost your job prospects with Github and blogging</li>
<li>The value of community involvement<div style="text-align: left;"></div></li>
</ul>
<p>If there are any topics you want to see or have written on this subject, please leave a comment on this post or get in touch.</p>
<h1 id="Its-not-just-developers-its-not-just-men"><a href="#Its-not-just-developers-its-not-just-men" class="headerlink" title="Its not just developers, its not just men!"></a>Its not just developers, its not just men!</h1><p>The people I met at the Kings College event were mainly interested in development roles, although some were asking about consultancy, some about the business side of IT and even had a great talk with one person creating their own startup company (and looking for developers to help him).</p>
<p>It was also great to see a mixture of men and women at the event, with an approximate 40% to 60% ratio.  Its wonderful to see software development attracting so many different people.</p>
<h1 id="Discussing-startups"><a href="#Discussing-startups" class="headerlink" title="Discussing startups"></a>Discussing startups</h1><img src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-ohLQrcWjBhg/UJKLz_Gl1MI/AAAAAAAAIeo/x2-5tLOFkX8/s1600/lean-startup-principles.png" class="img-topic"> 
<p>As I mentioned, I had a very long chat with someone in the student union bar afterwards about finding developers and other options to getting there startup going with minimal risk.&nbsp; Starting your own business is a great adventure and its very simple to get going.&nbsp; All you need is an idea and less than £100 to register a company and buy a domain name.&nbsp; The real trick is actually making money though!</p>
<p>We talked around the idea of a Minimal Viable Product (MVP), essentially thinking about the smallest most valuable service or product you could offer to your customers and find out quickly if anyone is interested.&nbsp; If you invest 3 months of your time and money before you find out if anyone will pay you for something then its a big risk!&nbsp; If you can get something out there in 3 days, getting very fast feedback, reducing the the pain of failure and affording you the opportunity to fail quite a few times.&nbsp; This fast feedback approach helps you fail fast and learn quickly from your failures and eventually find a sustainable business.</p>
<img src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-Kll1egLoCTk/UJKKRw0CFII/AAAAAAAAIeY/CwWePsNNtZM/s1600/forward-internet-logo-basic.png" class="img-topic"> 
<p>I told the story that now seems to be urban legend, regarding Forward Internet and the Pet Store.&nbsp; Forward create the most successfully pet store business in the UK, all from one of there team not finding anywhere they could buy a parrot cage on the Internet.&nbsp; Forward tested the demand for parrot cages by creating a mock website and collecting email addresses of those interested.&nbsp; Once they understood the demand in terms of scale and desirable products, they moved quickly to provide the a real service.</p>
<p>Using cages and other accessories manufactured in China, a cargo service that delivered containers of product to the UK and a logistics service that would unpack the cargo ships, package and deliver the cages to their customers, Forward was increadibly successful all without handling an actual cage themselves.&nbsp; Its a great example of creating a business from an idea and something all companies should invest more in, whether they be a startup or not.</p>
<h1 id="In-Summary"><a href="#In-Summary" class="headerlink" title="In Summary"></a>In Summary</h1><p>The Graduate Developer Community was started by Barry Cranford, CTO  of RecWorks, and only works due to the effort of mentors and the great  people at RecWorks.&nbsp; I enjoy meeting students and getting asked interesting and challenging questions (the simplest ones are usually the most challenging), its a great way to help me understand what I do every day.</p>
<p>If you are a student or recent graduate, then come along to a meet the mentor session.&nbsp; If you have been in industry for 5+ years then volunteer to be a mentor, its amazing fun!</p>
<p>Thank you.<br><a href="https://twitter.com/jr0cket" target="_blank" rel="noopener">jr0cket</a></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<img src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-aqvkk1hXMKs/UJKPf9DH41I/AAAAAAAAIfA/6nRGAqOmupI/s1600/gdc-logo.jpg" class="img-thumbnail">
<p>It was great to meet so many eager minds at Kings College during the Meet a Mentor session for the Graduate Developer community.</p>
<p>Kings College is a stunning setting for helping students understand the expectations that will be put upon them when they get into industry.</p>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="gdc" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/tags/gdc/"/>
    
      <category term="mentoring" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/tags/mentoring/"/>
    
      <category term="events" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/categories/events/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[London Scala Hackday Powered by Heroku]]></title>
    <link href="http://jr0cket.co.uk/2012/10/london-scala-hackathon-powered-by-heroku.html.html"/>
    <id>http://jr0cket.co.uk/2012/10/london-scala-hackathon-powered-by-heroku.html.html</id>
    <published>2012-10-30T14:32:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-02T20:20:15.306Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Saturday 27th saw a great hackday thanks to <a href="https://twitter.com/rrees" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Robert Rees</a>, The Guardian and members of the <a href="http://www.meetup.com/london-scala/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">London Scala user group</a>.  The ambitious challenge was to build an community website where events, conferences, blogs, code repos and  community discussions were all available from one place.</p>
<p>There are several websites out there that do a part of what a community  needs, to this project is trying to help bring all that together in one  place.  So the grand plans include, pulling in content from event sites,  publishing events to sites, register at events with a single touch and  widely distribute your interest and attendance automatically.</p>
<p>Or just have fun hacking on some cool technology and learning something new.</p>
<a id="more"></a>
<h1 id="The-basic-architecture"><a href="#The-basic-architecture" class="headerlink" title="The basic architecture"></a>The basic architecture</h1><p>The hack used the <a href="http://www.playframework.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Play framework</a>, a recent development that makes developer lives easy when building web applications.  A project had been started a couple of weeks ago using Play Framework 2.0.3 although as there was a new update, we moved to 2.0.4 during the hackathon.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.heroku.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Heroku</a> has been used as the deployment platform as it makes everything really easy.  You can deploy with a commit to a git repository.  So long as your build file works locally, then you can deploy on Heroku.</p>
<p>As we were using Heroku, we made use of <a href="https://addons.heroku.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">several addons availalbe</a>, specifically adding <a href="https://addons.heroku.com/mongolab" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MongoDB</a> to the design.  MongoDB would be used to pull in information from sites  that had a limited hit rate.  Mongo could also be used for holding any  adhoc data we wanted to keep around.</p>
<h1 id="The-deployment-process"><a href="#The-deployment-process" class="headerlink" title="The deployment process"></a>The deployment process</h1><img src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-qlVcL6zWbjY/TzFMw8PPiGI/AAAAAAAAEbs/-Ozv0X_6mrQ/s1600/github-logo.png" class="img-topic">
<p>Andy Hicks, our beloved community leader created a play framework project.  Then set up an heroku account, adding a couple of extra people as collaborators to be responsible for pushing changes to live.</p>
<p>Although we could just deploy directly onto heroku, its useful to <a href="http://www.github.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Github</a> as your development repository.</p>
<p>Using Github, you can manage the code base by forking the main repo and submitting change via github pull requests.  This encourages developers to commit often and make smaller changes, essential things if you only have a few hours to get things live.</p>
<h1 id="Continually-deploying"><a href="#Continually-deploying" class="headerlink" title="Continually deploying"></a>Continually deploying</h1><img src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-Gpk2Bz1KOSU/UI_b8kGF5fI/AAAAAAAAIeA/0tjExsTaL6E/s1600/lsug-hackathon-commit-graph-text.png" class="img-topic"> 
<p>Even though we were first commiting changes to github, we still pushed the  changes to Heroku regularly.  I would push changes up to Heroku after each pull request had been successfully merged.</p>
<p>If there were multiple pull requests waiting (usually due to fixing a conflicting pull request) then I’d merge all the outstanding requests before pushing to heroku.</p>
<p>The deployment process was essentially myself pulling changes from the github repository to my laptop, then pushing everything to the heroku git repository.</p>
<h1 id="Keeping-up-to-date"><a href="#Keeping-up-to-date" class="headerlink" title="Keeping up to date"></a>Keeping up to date</h1><p>One trick we learnt to make things easier is the <code>git stash</code> command.  If you have been working away on your code and realised you  were behind master, you can hide away the changes in your working copy  and git pull from the master without loosing your changes.</p>
<p>When you run the command <code>git stash pop</code> then your working copy changes are re-applied and you can resolve any confilcts you have before commiting.</p>
<pre><code>git stash
git pull lsugweb master
git stash pop 
&lt;resolve any conflicts&gt;
</code></pre><p>Alternatively, if you are doing more experimentation then a branch was created to work  on which would then be merged and committed into master if it was valuable code.</p>
<pre><code>git branch branch-name
&lt;edit you code base&gt;
git merge branch-name master
</code></pre><h1 id="Challenges"><a href="#Challenges" class="headerlink" title="Challenges"></a>Challenges</h1><p><strong>Git experience</strong>:<br>Although git is very popular now, many developers are still learning how to use it effectively, especially when working collaboratively.  </p>
<p><strong>.gitignore</strong>:<br>We had quite a few conflicting pull requests due to the <code>.gitignore</code> file.  So to keep things simple we agreed to keep changes to <code>.gitignore</code> seperate from code commits.  Likewise with any other non-essential config changes.  Add <strong>.gitignore</strong> to <code>.gitignore</code> and just  maintain a managed set of ignore files</p>
<p><strong>Keep commits small:</strong>:<br>Its  was so much easier to merge a series of small changes when you are using pull requests, especially when you have someone managing the queue  and can merge those changes quickly.  The bigger the commit, the longer it takes to merge and backs up your pull requests.  Our largest commit affected 73 files and it took several attempts before we could get it to automatically merge.  At least it gave us chance to talk about the  change in more detail.</p>
<p>It was a great hackathon and thanks to everyone that came along, <a href="https://twitter.com/rrees" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Robert Rees</a> for orgaising and The Guardian for hosting us.  Why not get yourself to a hackathon and join in the fun, or even organise your own ?</p>
<p>Thank you.<br><a href="https://twitter.com/jr0cket" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@jr0cket</a></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Saturday 27th saw a great hackday thanks to <a href="https://twitter.com/rrees" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Robert Rees</a>, The Guardian and members of the <a href="http://www.meetup.com/london-scala/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">London Scala user group</a>.  The ambitious challenge was to build an community website where events, conferences, blogs, code repos and  community discussions were all available from one place.</p>
<p>There are several websites out there that do a part of what a community  needs, to this project is trying to help bring all that together in one  place.  So the grand plans include, pulling in content from event sites,  publishing events to sites, register at events with a single touch and  widely distribute your interest and attendance automatically.</p>
<p>Or just have fun hacking on some cool technology and learning something new.</p>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="heroku" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/tags/heroku/"/>
    
      <category term="scala" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/tags/scala/"/>
    
      <category term="hackday" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/tags/hackday/"/>
    
      <category term="events" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/categories/events/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[IBM and the Irony of Community Engagement]]></title>
    <link href="http://jr0cket.co.uk/2012/10/ibm-and-irony-of-community-engagement.html.html"/>
    <id>http://jr0cket.co.uk/2012/10/ibm-and-irony-of-community-engagement.html.html</id>
    <published>2012-10-18T09:05:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-02T20:20:15.302Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-e1e0uoicAo4/UH-93ST7C7I/AAAAAAAAIZc/Mi7ucIjUk5o/s1600/jax-london-2012-logo.png" class="img-thumbnail"> 
<p>At the <a href="http://jaxlondon.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">JAX London conference</a> yesterday <a href="http://uk.linkedin.com/pub/steve-poole/10/803/477" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steve Poole of IBM</a> gave an inspiring speech, discussing the value of the right mix of business and open source participation in the development of Java.  The same day, IBM decides to no longer support the yearly <a href="http://conf.londonjavacommunity.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">London Java Community conference</a>.  This does beg the question, does IBM understand the message they are communicating?</p>
<img src="http://blog.sugati.nl/wp-content/uploads/2008/05/duke_evolution-300x139.jpg" class="img-topic"> 
<p>If you give a rallying call to the developers out there to help Oracle and IBM shape Java, then you also need to support that call and not just rely on the resource of that community.</p>
<p>Having asked IBM if the London Java Community could again use their great venue for their yearly conference, it seems the initial reply was yes, yes, yes, followed by a final response that they didn’t have the budget for us to us there venue.  Maybe some one at IBM misunderstood the request. </p>
<img src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/--aarZnZgEgA/UH_DNtHov_I/AAAAAAAAIZ4/azETKEhZG-k/s1600/ibm-logo.png" class="img-topic"> 
<p>I am sure that IBM contribute to the developer community in many ways, although as an organisation I have the perception it still struggles to understand the value of community, as Oracle once used to do.  To me it seems to let down the amazing individuals at IBM who have contributed greatly to the community as well as a huge opportunity to get developers involved in IBM technology and products.  It seems IBM are not helping themselves be the drivers of community engagement, which is a missed opportunity by them. </p>
<p>Over the last 5 years, the <a href="http://www.meetup.com/Londonjavacommunity/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">London Java Community</a> have been driving Java developer engagement with activities such as <a href="http://londonjavacommunity.wordpress.com/2011/09/29/adopt-a-jsr/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Adopt a JSR</a>, a yearly <a href="http://conf.londonjavacommunity.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">community conference</a> and <a href="http://www.meetup.com/Londonjavacommunity/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">regular community events</a>.  We have been very grateful to IBM for providing us use of their space for our yearly conference in the past, but it seems IBM dont have the budget this year for one Saturday. This is a bit disappointing as after a long process we only find out now, about 5 weeks before the conference.  Whilst there is no expectation for IBM to provide a venue, it is a great way that they can easily support the Java community in the UK.  It seems doubly disappointing considering the great sessions by Steve Poole and Holly Cummins at JAX London that inspired over 500 developers across a dozen countries to get involved with Java’s future and some cool IBM technology.</p>
<img src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-DnE0_spNbOM/T0Y2wWJQlTI/AAAAAAAAEsk/CJs7u9Z4JtY/s1600/big-yawn.jpg" class="img-topic"> 
<p>This situation does highlight how difficult it is for large companies to engage with the community.  If all you do is ask people to help, you probably wont get much reply without the perception of reciprocity!</p>
<p>With the support of IBM, Oracle, Atlassian, O’Reilly and others the London Java Community has been able to get so many more developers engaged with the development of the Java language.  As we have grown to ~3000 members, we can do event more when working with partners that understand the value of community engagement, to help us help developers get involved in the future shape of Java.</p>
<p>Sponsors have real value to gain by investing in community activity and developer groups like the <a href="http://www.meetup.com/Londonjavacommunity/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Java</a>, <a href="http://www.meetup.com/london-scala/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Scala</a>, <a href="http://www.meetup.com/london-software-craftsmanship/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Craftmanship</a> and <a href="https://groups.google.com/group/london-clojurians" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Clojure</a> communities allow a means to invest in communities in a way that is valued by the developers in those community.</p>
<p>If you want the community to engage with you, you have to stay relevant and give developers inspiration, motivation and the means to get involved.  IBM have given the community a perception of a really big push and fail in the same day.  That is itself is quite a trick.</p>
<p>The <a href="http://conf.londonjavacommunity.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">London Java Community conference</a> is going ahead as planned and registration will open as soon as we confirm a new venue, so please save the date of <strong>Saturday 24th November</strong>.</p>
<p>Thank you<br><a href="https://twitter.com/jr0cket" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@jr0cket</a></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<img src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-e1e0uoicAo4/UH-93ST7C7I/AAAAAAAAIZc/Mi7ucIjUk5o/s1600/jax-london-2012-logo.png" class="img-thumbnail"> 
]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="events" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/categories/events/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[London Salesforce Developers - Dreamforce Aftermath]]></title>
    <link href="http://jr0cket.co.uk/2012/10/london-salesforce-developers-dreamforce.html.html"/>
    <id>http://jr0cket.co.uk/2012/10/london-salesforce-developers-dreamforce.html.html</id>
    <published>2012-10-12T16:17:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-02T20:20:15.306Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://flic.kr/s/aHsjCfs8vJ" class="img-thumbnail">
<p>Over 7,000 developers flocked to the <a href="http://events.developerforce.com/conference/dreamforce" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DevZone</a> at this years Dreamforce conference.  I was one of them and along with Adam Seligman, Keir Bowden and Andy Mahood we told tales of our experiences to the <a href="http://www.meetup.com/LondonSalesforceDevelopers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">London Salesforce Developer community</a>.</p>
<p>Wes Nolte took charge of the mike and quizzed the panel on their experiences of the event.  Here are the questions that stuck in my memory from the evening</p>
<h1 id="What-was-the-thing-that-got-you-most-excited-about-Dreamforce"><a href="#What-was-the-thing-that-got-you-most-excited-about-Dreamforce" class="headerlink" title="What was the thing that got you most excited about Dreamforce ?"></a>What was the thing that got you most excited about Dreamforce ?</h1><p>The thing that got to me was the sheer size of it all.  With so many developers around it was great that we had a whole of Moscone West to spread it all out.  There were banks of laptops provided for anyone to get involved in coding workshops and all through the day they were all filled up.</p>
<p>There were so many different things to do, from playing donkey kong to coding, listening to great talks, guided tutorials, code consultations and quizing lots of people from Salesforce and Heroku about their platforms.</p>
<img src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-iFOo-wRJGSo/UHg8hxE5Q1I/AAAAAAAAIYc/iSZB4mCa7dk/s1600/dreamforce-devs-tshirt-printing.png" class="img-code">
<p>The biggest problem was what to actually do from so much choice.  Of course there was an app for that too and a chatter stream so you could discuss sessions as well.</p>
<p>If you couldn’t make up your mind you could also queue up and print your own t-shirt!</p>
<p>It was a sign of how open the conference was to have an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unconference" target="_blank" rel="noopener">un-conference</a> section, where anyone could propose a talk.  There was even a theatre dedicated to community related talks.  I met some great guys from Bristol who are starting up their own Salesforce community events.</p>
<h1 id="What-was-your-favourite-session"><a href="#What-was-your-favourite-session" class="headerlink" title="What was your favourite session ?"></a>What was your favourite session ?</h1><p>The most entertaining session was by <a href="http://redmonk.com/jgovernor/2012/09/21/dreamforce-12-crazy-big-with-lower-barriers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">James Governor from RedMonk</a>, comparing the rise of craft brewing with the rise of developers.  Craft brewing is bringing back the entrepreneurial flavour into beer making and bringing quality product to the market. Developers are doing the same for startups and enterprises around the world.  Calling developers the new kingmakers, James highlights how important developers are and the responsibility we have on our shoulders to support the businesses and projects we are involved in. See article….</p>
<p>I also really enjoyed the live coding challenges from MVP developers and developer evangelists.  There was a great banter as well as great code being bashed out.</p>
<img src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ZwXY5J6tDHc/UHg78yqt0QI/AAAAAAAAIYU/zaOPW6R6pSg/s1600/dreamforce-devs-collaborating.png" class="img-code">
<p>My favourite moment was when one of my colleagues was presenting.  They had a great presentation line up, all using on-line resources and then the wireless failed.  Before the venue tech guys had chance to fix it, someone from the audience donated their phone and the presentation was on again.  I had a warm fuzzy feeling about that!</p>
<p>All through the conference there was a feeling of collaboration and community.  Whether that be debugging each others code through the workshops or collaborating on the mini-hacks.  There was a constant stream of activity every day.</p>
<p>Have a look at <a href="http://developer.force.com/dreamforce" target="_blank" rel="noopener">all the videos and code</a> produced at the DevZone this year and see for yourself.</p>
<h1 id="What-new-stuff-are-you-already-using-or-want-to-try-straight-away"><a href="#What-new-stuff-are-you-already-using-or-want-to-try-straight-away" class="headerlink" title="What new stuff are you already using or want to try straight away ?"></a>What new stuff are you already using or want to try straight away ?</h1><p>In a nutshell, it has to mobile development.  I remember spending a day in a workshop getting up to speed with development on Android devices and there was still lots to learn by the time I had finished.  That seems like a lifetime compared what I saw at Dreamforce.  Using the Salesforce Touch platform you can easily and quickly build HTML5 and hybrid applications in be finished in hours, not days.</p>
<p>It seemed the hardest thing for mobile development using the Touch platform was registering for your Apple ID.</p>
<h1 id="Turing-the-tables-on-the-audience"><a href="#Turing-the-tables-on-the-audience" class="headerlink" title="Turing the tables on the audience"></a>Turing the tables on the audience</h1><p>At the end we turned the tables and each panellist got to ask a question of the audience.</p>
<p>I wanted to shorten our name from “Salesforce platform developers user group London”, not the easiest thing to tell your friends about.  From the feedback we got we have changed it to the punchier <a href="http://www.meetup.com/LondonSalesforceDevelopers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">London Salesforce Developers</a>, which encompasses the different platforms (heroku, force.com, data,com, etc) under one name.</p>
<h1 id="Summary"><a href="#Summary" class="headerlink" title="Summary"></a>Summary</h1><p>Over 80 developers braved the cold October night to hear about out experiences and it was a great social event, made even better by the beer and pizza provided by <a href="http://www.tquila.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tquila</a>.</p>
<p>Thanks also to our gratious hosts, 10Gen, for providing the venue.  10Gen are the company behind the popular MongoDB.</p>
<p>Thank you.<br><a href="https://twitter.com/jr0cket" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@jr0cket</a></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<img src="http://flic.kr/s/aHsjCfs8vJ" class="img-thumbnail">
<p>Over 7,000 developers flocked to the <a href="http://events.developerforce.]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="heroku" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/tags/heroku/"/>
    
      <category term="salesforce" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/tags/salesforce/"/>
    
      <category term="events" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/categories/events/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Agile Cambridge 2012 Aftermath]]></title>
    <link href="http://jr0cket.co.uk/2012/10/agile-cambridge-2012-aftermath.html.html"/>
    <id>http://jr0cket.co.uk/2012/10/agile-cambridge-2012-aftermath.html.html</id>
    <published>2012-10-07T13:25:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-02T20:20:15.290Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-OJOQHJuBmYI/UHFDixa7fvI/AAAAAAAAIXQ/bFfSJSVwgMc/s1600/Agile-Cambridge-2012-600x125.jpg" class="img-thumbnail"> 
<p>An event full of discovery, psychology, therapy sessions, learning, juggling and lots more fun, that in a nutshell was <a href="http://www.agilecambridge.net/ac2012/index.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Agile Cambridge 2012</a>.!  It was great to meet old friends and new as well as sit in on some great sessions.  Here are just a few of my personal highlights from the conference.</p>
<h1 id="Cynifin-dealing-with-uncertainty"><a href="#Cynifin-dealing-with-uncertainty" class="headerlink" title="Cynifin - dealing with uncertainty"></a>Cynifin - dealing with uncertainty</h1><p>In hindsight there was a theme of “dealing with uncertainty” running through the conference, but I  guess when that is the consistent thread in our lives then its hard to  get away from that pattern anyway.</p>
<img src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-REbcZKZoyAY/UHFDN_11hgI/AAAAAAAAIXI/8zdrayvVxn8/s1600/Cynefin_framework_Feb_2011.jpeg" class="img-topic">
<p>This is the first time I managed to see Dave Snowden (<a href="http://www.twitter.com/snowded" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@snowded</a>) talk about his <a href="http://cognitive-edge.com/library/more/video/introduction-to-the-cynefin-framework/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cynifin model</a> for dealing with uncertainty and it was worth the wait.  Whilst I have  seen several people talk about Cynifin before, Dave really conveys the value and importance of the model like no other.</p>
<p>Cynefin  is a Welsh word that means “the place of your multiple belongings”.   Essentially it refers to the fact that there are thousands of things in  your experience that influence your understanding and you can never be  fully aware of them or their affect.</p>
<p>Humans evolved to  make decisions  very quickly as tigers tend not to wait for a project budget before they  eat you.  We are therefore very good at making decisions based on  partial requirements and past experience.  We also focus on the negative  as unfortunately avoidance of failure is more  attractive than following success.</p>
<p>Cynefin is a “sense making” framework to help you understand and manage complex and complicated situations.  Dependent on which of the four domains you are in, simple, complicated, complex &amp; chaotic defines how you should think and analyse the situation.</p>
<p>In a simple domain then you can easily categorise the situation and deal with it appropriately.  A software development team is rarely a simple domain and tends to fluctuate between complex and complicated domains, driven by the unpredictable nature of the businesses they support.</p>
<p>The Cynefin model looks a great way to think about the situations I am in  and its a big take away to try and apply it to my working practices. </p>
<h1 id="Cracking-your-big-rocks"><a href="#Cracking-your-big-rocks" class="headerlink" title="Cracking your big rocks"></a>Cracking your big rocks</h1><img src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-Z76s9Q39Rq0/UHFFlq-q0TI/AAAAAAAAIXY/PBs-UBiFfQk/s1600/cracking-a-big-rock.png" class="img-theme">
<p>Some tasks seem to us to be so out of our scope, so unfamiliar or painful to  do that we will do anything else to avoid doing them.  These tasks that  become unmovable and intractable in our minds and cause us to waste too much time thinking about not doing them.  These are our Big Rocks!</p>
<p><a href="http://www.agilecambridge.net/ac2012/sessioninfo.php?session=23" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cracking your big rocks</a> was another example of a great coaching session, specifically to help us break down some ones big rocks.</p>
<p>Assembling in groups of 4, one person had a big rock, two were coaching and one had a deck of big rock cards.  The coaches helped the person understand  the challenge of their big rock and encouraged them to find ways that they could start to break it down.  The cards were used to help shape  the coaching discussion or highlight concepts the coaches raised.  Cards  covered techniques for framing the problem, keeping rolling, saving progress as well as anti-patterns.</p>
<h2 id="My-Rock"><a href="#My-Rock" class="headerlink" title="My Rock"></a>My Rock</h2><p>I was the person with a big rock, mine was writing a book (although much  applied to other writing too).  I never seemed to have enough time to  write the book, was overly concerned about quality and had many other personal and professional tasks pulling me away from the book writing.  The coaches helped me break down the challenge, so rather than writing chapters at a time I started to focus on sections in a chapter.  A section could be done in an hour or less and I could give myself a micro-break and decide whether to continue or re-prioritise.</p>
<p>I’ve  never seen Johanna Hunt and Simon Cromarty talk before and was really impressed with their session, the way they bounce the conversation between themselves and the audience was really engaging.</p>
<h1 id="Coaching-techniques"><a href="#Coaching-techniques" class="headerlink" title="Coaching techniques"></a>Coaching techniques</h1><p>Leaning to be an effective coach is very  challenging so its great to learn new techniques to help.  Using the simple props of juggling balls, we coached each other in how to juggle</p>
<img src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-A7etqPlGrY8/UHF-1dLiPmI/AAAAAAAAIXs/JFwKYbygf0g/s1600/juggling-hand-and-ball.jpg" class="img-topic"> 
<p>Where no one in a group had any experience of juggling, it was a case of the blind leading the blind.  In this situation one group decided to gate-crash a few other groups, observing what they were doing and learning by figuring out where the juggling experience was.</p>
<p>Coaching someone to juggle is a great exampel of where experience of the skill can bring a lot of value to the coaching.  </p>
<p>In  my group, Simon and Nasim were pretty expert jugglers.  Simon had no problem understanding what I should be doing to juggle, the  challenge for him however was to coach me rather than teach me - two  very different things with different results.  By suggesting things I could try and encouraging me to thing about what I was doing I soon gained more confidence.   Nasim was observing Simon coach me and at the end of my basic juggling  session, he gave feedback on what he saw.  </p>
<p>When Nasim was coaching Simon he was a bit taken aback by Simon’s level of skill and wasnt sure how to coach him as he was already doing so well.  However, by talking to Simon about his juggling technique he was able to  relate to him better a juggler of equal skill.  Also asking Simon what he wanted to achieve from the session helped set a goal for Nasim and Simon to get to, framing the session nicely.  In this case Simon wanted to learn to juggle with 4 balls, so Nasim encouraged Simon to understand his technique so he could build on it and find a way to  achieve his goal.</p>
<p>When it was my turn to coach, I  encouraged Nasim to vary his technique, to go back to basic principles and to gradually introduce more balls into the mix.  I typically asked lots of simple questions about juggling to prevent Nasim from over-thinking the task.  I also asked emotional questions, such as which technique feels better, to gauge if I was helping Nasim keep in a positive state of mind.</p>
<p>By asking us to coach someone in a technique that we were not familiar with was a good way to practice our core skills as a coach, especially our ability to assess the situation, listen and gain understanding of the other persons objectives.  As an agile coach, it is very easy for the agile practices and mindset to dominate the conversation and activities, when doing something that most people were not used to coaching it really helped us get back to  basics.</p>
<h1 id="One-Man-Dan"><a href="#One-Man-Dan" class="headerlink" title="One Man Dan"></a>One Man Dan</h1><p>It was great to hear from Dan North (<a href="http://www.twitter.com/tastapod" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@tastapod</a>) again, he is always entertaining and thought provoking.  Dan is embarking on his solo career and will be hitting 13 different events  between now and the December holidays.  His talk on embracing uncertainty complemented the opening keynote perfectly and highlighted how unpredictable software development is and why its wasteful to try create order.  Dan discussed the real value that can be attained by  accepting uncertainty and dealing with it gracefully.</p>
<h1 id="In-Summary"><a href="#In-Summary" class="headerlink" title="In Summary"></a>In Summary</h1><p>Conferences are a great way to discover new things as  well as catch up with friends and make new ones.  It was great to catch up with Dan North and find out about his new adventures, hear the agile coaching stories from John McFaden and meet Darcy D, another ex-thoughworker mixing UX development and agile coaching.</p>
<p>There were lots of sessions I didn’t get chance to see, so am looking forward to catching up with them on <a href="http://www.infoq.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">InfoQ</a> soon.</p>
<p>Thanks to <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/markdalgarnouk" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mark Delgarmo</a> and team for organising the event.  Special thanks to <a href="http://www.rallydev.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rally Software</a> for sponsoring the social event on Thursday night where I had some great conversations, delicious food and a pint or three of <a href="http://www.samuelsmithsbrewery.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Samuel Smiths beer</a>!</p>
<p>Hope to see you all at Agile Cambridge 2013!</p>
<p>Thank you.<br><a href="https://twitter.com/jr0cket" target="_blank" rel="noopener">jr0cket</a></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<img src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-OJOQHJuBmYI/UHFDixa7fvI/AAAAAAAAIXQ/bFfSJSVwgMc/s1600/Agile-Cambridge-2012-600x125.jpg" class="img-thumb]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="agile" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/tags/agile/"/>
    
      <category term="agilecambridge" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/tags/agilecambridge/"/>
    
      <category term="events" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/categories/events/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[UK Developer Startup Wins Aussie Gold]]></title>
    <link href="http://jr0cket.co.uk/2012/07/uk-developer-startup-wins-aussie-gold.html.html"/>
    <id>http://jr0cket.co.uk/2012/07/uk-developer-startup-wins-aussie-gold.html.html</id>
    <published>2012-07-25T14:45:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-02T20:20:15.310Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://hindsightsoftware.com/img/hindsight.png" class="img-thumbnail">
<blockquote><p>Coding is fun, its also great if you make some profit!</p>
</blockquote>
<p>UK developers lead by community expert Alan Parkinson recently formed<a href="http://hindsighttesting.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hindsight Software</a>, a start-up focused on bringing <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Behavior-driven_development" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Behaviour Driven Development</a> (BDD) to as wide an audience as possible.  With their first product <a href="https://marketplace.atlassian.com/plugins/com.hindsighttesting.behave.jira" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Behave for JIRA</a>, they entered into the <a href="https://marketplace.atlassian.com/codegeist" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Atlassian Codegeist</a> competition judged by Atlassian’s CEO Mike Cannon-Brookes. They scored a big win against a record number of entries in the annual competition.</p>
<a id="more"></a>
<p>Whilst there are some great tools BDD tools already out there, eg. <a href="http://cukes.info/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cucumber</a>, <a href="http://www.easyb.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">EasyB</a>, they suffer from usability issues when used by less technically oriented people.  <a href="https://marketplace.atlassian.com/plugins/com.hindsighttesting.behave.jira" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Behave for JIRA</a> makes it easy to use Cucumber style acceptance tests (using the Gherkin language) within a familiar and easy to use surrounding of JIRA tickets. </p>
<p>Getting started with the Atlassian platform was as easy as downloading the <a href="https://developer.atlassian.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">software development kit (SDK)</a> and following the wide range of tutorials available. Having worked on many JIRA integration projects before, it was easy enough for Hindsight to understand the overall approach and be aware of the challenges upfront (like deciding which version of the platform to target).</p>
<p>Selling the software through the <a href="https://marketplace.atlassian.com/plugins/com.hindsighttesting.behave.jira" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Atlassian marketplace</a> also minimised the non-coding work Hindsight had to do.  All that was required was to register their product on the Atlassian Marketplace website and within a day it was live. </p>
<p>For Hindsight is has been a great way to try out an idea without requiring massive investment in resources and technology, in the best tradition of a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lean_Startup" target="_blank" rel="noopener">lean startup</a>.  Eric Ries would be proud!</p>
<img src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-U_xit_Jp0hs/T_V3BFcfPuI/AAAAAAAAIOM/bBOHeizMysE/s1600/atlassian-usergroup-logo.png" class="img-topic">
<p>Hindsight are keen to do more in the UK to help encourage other developers to see the benefit of building on the Atlassian platform.  Even though they are already part of the community by helping run the London Atlassian user group, they are keen to run plug-in workshops and other practical activities that get developers really engaged.</p>
<p>If you are into <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Behavior-driven_development" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Behavour Driven Development</a>, or are looking for a way to manage requirements in a more humane way, then check out Behave for JIRA.</p>
<p>If you are a keen developer, have a look at the competition entries and think about what you could create for <a href="https://marketplace.atlassian.com/codegeist" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Codegeist</a> 2013 or other coding competitions year round!  Good luck.</p>
<p>Thank you.<br><a href="https://twitter.com/jr0cket" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@jr0cket</a></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<img src="http://hindsightsoftware.com/img/hindsight.png" class="img-thumbnail">
<blockquote><p>Coding is fun, its also great if you make some profit!</p>
</blockquote>
<p>UK developers lead by community expert Alan Parkinson recently formed<a href="http://hindsighttesting.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hindsight Software</a>, a start-up focused on bringing <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Behavior-driven_development" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Behaviour Driven Development</a> (BDD) to as wide an audience as possible.  With their first product <a href="https://marketplace.atlassian.com/plugins/com.hindsighttesting.behave.jira" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Behave for JIRA</a>, they entered into the <a href="https://marketplace.atlassian.com/codegeist" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Atlassian Codegeist</a> competition judged by Atlassian’s CEO Mike Cannon-Brookes. They scored a big win against a record number of entries in the annual competition.</p>]]>
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="atlassian" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/tags/atlassian/"/>
    
      <category term="hindsight" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/tags/hindsight/"/>
    
      <category term="events" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/categories/events/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Behavior Driven Development Coming to JIRA]]></title>
    <link href="http://jr0cket.co.uk/2012/07/behavior-driven-development-coming-to.html.html"/>
    <id>http://jr0cket.co.uk/2012/07/behavior-driven-development-coming-to.html.html</id>
    <published>2012-07-10T14:19:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-02T20:20:15.290Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-8m3b2IQ43Pw/T_w5KnL2L7I/AAAAAAAAIOY/8WLZ84PLJ2c/s1600/hindsight-testing-logo-300x61.png" class="img-thumbnail">
<p><a href="http://hindsighttesting.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hindsight</a> is a start-up  company focused on building intelligent testing software that supports agile practices such as acceptance testing.&nbsp; Using the <a href="https://marketplace.atlassian.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Atlassian Marketplace</a> to enable rapid development of their first tool, Behave for JIRA, they had a  platform to quickly deliverer a valuable product to a large number of  software teams around the world.</p>
<img src="http://atlassian.wpengine.netdna-cdn.com/wp-content/uploads/newslice-300x82.png" class="img-topic"> 
<p>Atlassian competitions such as <a href="https://marketplace.atlassian.com/codegeist" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Codegeist</a> showed Hindsight how easy it was to get started with plug-in  development with JIRA and inspired the team to secure funding for their  own product development. </p>
<p>Hindsight is passionate about software quality and is in the business  of providing tools to help everyone in the software development team  focus on quality of the delivered product.</p>
<p>Their first product, Behave for JIRA, brings acceptance testing to the  wealth of Atlassian customers around the world and at a lower cost of  entry into the market.&nbsp; If successful the company will look to extend  this service to the cloud.&nbsp; In the mean time the Atlassian market place  allows Hindsight to validate that their innovative solutions are  valuable to the market before they make a major infrastructure  investment</p>
<h2 id="Behave-for-JIRA-–-bringing-Acceptance-Testing-to-all-your-projects"><a href="#Behave-for-JIRA-–-bringing-Acceptance-Testing-to-all-your-projects" class="headerlink" title="Behave for JIRA – bringing Acceptance Testing to all your projects"></a>Behave for JIRA – bringing Acceptance Testing to all your projects</h2><p>Acceptance tests allow you to express specific needs for your  software product in a way that is testable and measurable.&nbsp; It is also  invaluable for breaking down the barriers in software development.</p>
<p>Behave for JIRA allows you to easily add acceptance tests to any issue in  your projects.&nbsp; Acceptance tests are written in a natural  language, eg. English, but in a structured way so that those needs can  be matched up to the software that is created to satisfy them.&nbsp; In <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Behavior_Driven_Development" title="Wikipedia - Behavior Driven Development" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Behaviour Driven Development</a> an example acceptance test would be:</p>
<pre><code>Given _a specific situation
When _something occurs
Then _you will get a specific outcome
</code></pre><p>The most commonly used acceptance testing framework is called <a href="http://cukes.info/" title="Cucumber - making BDD more fun" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cucumber</a> and supports many different software programming languages.&nbsp; Once you  have defined you acceptance criteria with JIRA Behave, you can then run  those tests with Cucumber to get instant feedback on you software  development progress.</p>
<p>As this is a plug-in for JIRA, you can easily make use of all the  data your projects and have a simple to use and powerful way to edit and  review your test specifications.&nbsp; This includes syntax highlighting  editor for quick authoring of requirements &amp; acceptance tests.</p>
<h2 id="Developing-products-using-Atlassian-tools"><a href="#Developing-products-using-Atlassian-tools" class="headerlink" title="Developing products using Atlassian tools"></a>Developing products using Atlassian tools</h2><p>As Hindsight have stakeholders with a vested interest in the success  of the company, they make use of the Atlassian tool-set to ensure  everyone is up to date with the progress of the software development.&nbsp;  Any non-technical people involved in the company can see the sprint  burn-down charts and understand the status.&nbsp; It is easy to see what is  planned and what the development team have committed to and hold the  team to account if they don’t meet the targets they set for themselves.</p>
<img src="http://atlassian.wpengine.netdna-cdn.com/wp-content/uploads/dragon-slayer-integration-dashboard-thumb-400x242.png" class="img-topic"> 
<p>For the developers, using <a href="http://blogs.atlassian.com/2012/07/atlassian-inspires-uk-testing-startup/www.atlassian.com/software/greenhopper" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GreenHopper</a> it was easy to see if things were going to over-run and a decision  could be made quickly about re-prioritising the work.&nbsp; As this all fed  into a JIRA dashboard for the stakeholders, communication about progress  was updated in real time.&nbsp; When two new graduates were on-boarded, it  took just two sprints to adjust their capability using <a href="http://blogs.atlassian.com/2012/07/atlassian-inspires-uk-testing-startup/www.atlassian.com/software/greenhopper" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GreenHopper</a> to track and review progress.</p>
<p>The development team uses a Scrum-like approach, base on a two week iteration.&nbsp; Using <a href="http://blogs.atlassian.com/2012/07/atlassian-inspires-uk-testing-startup/www.atlassian.com/software/greenhopper" target="_blank" rel="noopener">JIRA GreenHopper</a> scrum template made set-up of the project as simple as defining a  project name and pressing a few buttons. The team have also used the  rapid board to manage their individual responsibilities so they can  quickly priorities the features inside the sprint.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.hipchat.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hipchat</a> provides  an instant way for the team to to discuss challenges, especially when  they are apart.&nbsp; As Hipchat is also plugged into JIRA and their overall  build process, any significant changes in the project get broadcast on  the Hindsight Hipchat channel.&nbsp; This immediate feedback from build  servers, allows the team to quickly fix problems as they happen.</p>
<h1 id="3-most-valuable-practices"><a href="#3-most-valuable-practices" class="headerlink" title="3 most valuable practices"></a>3 most valuable practices</h1><p>1) Visibility to the business – stakeholders can see our commitments and easily hold us accountable</p>
<p>2) Distributed working is often a necessity and so having our up to  date progress accessible anywhere there is an Internet connection is  invaluable.&nbsp; Using Distributed Version control also means we can work  off line</p>
<p>3) In constant communication using <a href="http://www.hipchat.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hipchat</a> which also enables the team to see JIRA notifications on bug reports, issues re-opened tickets and other major events.</p>
<p><img src="http://atlassian.wpengine.netdna-cdn.com/wp-content/uploads/logoAtlassianPNG-300x92.png" class="img-topic"> Head over to <a href="http://www.atlassian.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Atlassian</a> to find out about their range of software for software developers and dont forget to checkout the <a href="https://marketplace.atlassian.com/codegeist" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Codegeist</a> competition (ends 16th July 2012).<br>Thank you.<br><a href="https://twitter.com/jr0cket" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@jr0cket</a></p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<img src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-8m3b2IQ43Pw/T_w5KnL2L7I/AAAAAAAAIOY/8WLZ84PLJ2c/s1600/hindsight-testing-logo-300x61.png" class="img-thum]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="atlassian" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/tags/atlassian/"/>
    
      <category term="hindsight" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/tags/hindsight/"/>
    
      <category term="events" scheme="http://jr0cket.co.uk/categories/events/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
